<data><subreddit>2shup<submission>6bra10<comments><comment><commentCreated>1495084500.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhoyph3</commentID><commentText>Do we even need this when we have the Brody Loving Center to meet people?</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6bkzi3<comments /></submission><submission>6baund<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494901626.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhldxy8</commentID><commentText>If you have the chance to take any poly sci courses taught by Daniel Deudney take them. I've only heard great things about him and the topics are usually really cool.</commentText><authorName>IncompetentPotato</authorName><authorID>h5h83</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494940065.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhm7rup</commentID><commentText>For math, Brown is especially great for freshman year because he's a generally pleasant man  
 For econ you're pretty much constrained to Elements of Macro with Barbera which isn't bad but I can't say that I particularly enjoyed it </commentText><authorName>kalotypography</authorName><authorID>fq5iu</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494966811.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhmipxj</commentID><commentText>Current student here. 

Since you have a wide range of interests, it can't hurt to take one lower level course in each of those Subject areas. I know my friends during their first year took Macroeconomics (Econ) and a decent number took Contemporary International Politics (IS/polysci). I've heard good things about professor Steven David in International Studies as well. For math, the lower level courses are usually taught be circulating professors (i.e. The prof switched each semester). But I recommend taking courses with Dr. Brown when possible since I've heard good things (he's head of Math Dept). 

Do you have a major in mind? And do you have a possible class schedule yet? If so, let me know and I can give more specific feedback!</commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1495001946.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhndkzi</commentID><commentText>Since covered grades are done, I want an easier start to Hopkins so I'm trying to find classes with teachers that are more generous. I want to major in econ or IS (leaning towards econ but could be both). </commentText><authorName>maxnks</authorName><authorID>yesc1</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494911682.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhlmq8p</commentID><commentText>For poli sci Sheingate is great.</commentText><authorName>ac91</authorName><authorID>658hi</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494936645.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhm5uvu</commentID><commentText>They didn't get rid of covered grades yet right? If they still exist, try and take a difficult class or two so you have protection on your transcript while you acclimate. 

Tell us your major for some better recommendations..</commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6b4ek8<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494817514.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhjx6tt</commentID><commentText>I'm pretty sure it's in the myJHU area somewhere.  I clicked around until I found a profile page.  I can look when I get home if you still can't find it </commentText><authorName>jonsam201</authorName><authorID>g8ssp</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494858569.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhkoycr</commentID><commentText>There are issues with the Emergency Alert sign-ups that their IT is looking into right now. I ran into the same problem, but it should be fixed soon.

Congrats on getting in btw, what are you majoring in?</commentText><authorName>TheAsianIsGamin</authorName><authorID>eezfl</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6b1tbc<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494771878.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhjaeif</commentID><commentText>I lived up by Towson while in grad school. that's a bit far without a car though</commentText><authorName>minotaurbear</authorName><authorID>ccgge</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494786971.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhjf9nz</commentID><commentText>PhD or masters?  Some people in my dept(physics) have actually bought houses.  My wife and I did in Ednor Gardens, love it here. graduate students are often less tied to living super close to the university, so you might want to hit up /r/Baltimore for general tips on where to look </commentText><authorName>PhononMagnon</authorName><authorID>6j9sd</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494798059.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhjjpr2</commentID><commentText>It depends on what you want, but if you are a PhD student, I recommend buying a rowhouse or something because (a) parts of Baltimore are improving and (b) you're going to be here a while... a long while.</commentText><authorName>Molozonide</authorName><authorID>47dft</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494849271.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhkkgsl</commentID><commentText>Don't recommend the giant apartment complexes--they usually overcharge by a lot, constantly have problems, and because you are living around so many people, bugs, mice, and other pest problems are more likely.  Highly recommend the CV area if you're going to be near Homewood.  Hampden is popular, but if you have a car, parking can be a HUGE pain in the ass.  You can walk/bike easily from CV up to Hampden; I do it all of the time. 

If you do decide CV, a row home is optimal.  The closer you get to Greenmount you get though the worst it gets.  Stay roughly around the Calvert/St. Paul area from above 29th street.  Remington is also up and coming and you can bike/walk from there.  There are some very good restaurants and cafes around Remington.  For Remington stay closer to Maryland Ave, East of Howard and above 26th-27th street.  

If you are going to work at JHMI I recommend anything in Canton, but below Patterson Park.  I used to live in Butcher's Hill and had my house broken into and my roommate had his car window smashed.  People will tell you Upper Fells, but it can be a mixed bag--people get robbed and assaulted (during all times of day--even while walking to work in the morning) alllllllllllllll the time around Fayette, Washington, Wolfe, and Caroline (below Orleans/Rt 40).  Anything really below the park is the safest option.  

The other popular option is Mt. Vernon, but I can't recommend it at all.  Parking is infinitely worse than Hampden and, I know this is my own opinion, but a lot of the stuff there (restaurants/bars/etc.) are completely overrated.  Plus rent is higher and it isn't always the safest.  People are constantly assaulted and accosted at gun point around Mt. Vernon.  If you have to get between both campuses the JHMI shuttle for Mt. Vernon can suckkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkkk.  And that's an understatement.  The problem is Mt. Vernon gets screwed because they're sort of right in the middle, and during rush hour the shuttles are always full and constantly have to skip the Mt. Vernon people.  I can't tell you how much that sucks when it is raining or freezing outside.  </commentText><authorName>_IDriveADodgeStratus</authorName><authorID>reffm</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1495106850.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhpgo06</commentID><commentText>What about Abell Ave in Charles Village? I'm also starting as a grad student in the fall and I've noticed a lot of houses for rent there, but it's kind of close to the sketchier parts of town. </commentText><authorName>a2z95</authorName><authorID>mdd34</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6b1rrt<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494769304.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhj9bu6</commentID><commentText>How did you do on your Lin alg midterms/final?</commentText><authorName>wowfuckthisshit</authorName><authorID>we6b2</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494798452.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhjjxdf</commentID><commentText>What is your in-major GPA? And your overall GPA? I think it's fine to have a couple bad grades as long as it's not a trend.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6b1rol<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494794476.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhjhxcw</commentID><commentText>The Hopkins shuttle is reliable. I live in mt Vernon and take the shuttle in every day. I used to go a bit mad, but they added a bus tracking app (transloc rider) so I can at least see where the bus is. In the morning and evening the bus runs frequently enough that the waits are never more than 15 minutes. </commentText><authorName>trashacount12345</authorName><authorID>3w2ki</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494849559.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhkkmq5</commentID><commentText>Recommend a row home in CV/Remington.  I guess if you don't have a car then Hampden is good.  Can always bike.  If you don't have  a car then either think about doing zip cars to go grocery shopping or you'll have to take the Hopkins shuttle to Giant. Not sure what your cup of tea is, but Giant is just your regular 'ol grocer.   If you do end up in Hampden you can also walk to Mom's which has a lot of fancier/organic higher quality food.  

Don't underestimate how much of a PITA it can be to do laundry/get groceries/a haircut/need a pharmacy etc....</commentText><authorName>_IDriveADodgeStratus</authorName><authorID>reffm</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6av4qr<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494670328.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhhr4wc</commentID><commentText>I enjoyed it and did it for both clinical and research. Pretty standard questions that don't throw any tough questions. Be prepared to explain your interest in the tutorials and or your selection(s). Was helpful for giving me good experiences.</commentText><authorName>PhosphoErk</authorName><authorID>newap</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6apm4f<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494635040.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhgzfvk</commentID><commentText>Yup. 

https://www.facebook.com/BaltimoreCityPolice/posts/10154377779561956?comment_id=10154377798076956&amp;notif_t=like&amp;notif_id=1494605988017358

&gt; Further investigation revealed the suspect to be 19 year-old Advaith Baimeedi of the 3300 block of Saint Paul Street. Detectives were then able to locate the suspect.

Said he did it on a dare...I think he was dared to stop finals from happening.</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494622243.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhgoywk</commentID><commentText>Wasn't me</commentText><authorName>skiguy0123</authorName><authorID>68slc</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494972124.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhmmiez</commentID><commentText>Looks like he finally made bail yesterday afternoon. That must have been a shitty weekend for him. </commentText><authorName>TakeshiKido</authorName><authorID>1735jc</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6aoxuz<comments><comment><commentCreated>1495137000.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhptvhn</commentID><commentText>While it has cons, if you specifically want to meet the most people, AMR2 is your best bet. I didn't have a roommate, but my friends who generally looked for roommates on the fb page were happier with their eventual roommates (for the most part) than those who didn't.</commentText><authorName>iainttalkingvegan</authorName><authorID>1fyv95t</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6ao7h4<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494634472.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhgyxum</commentID><commentText>Taken it, easy. I had J paschke</commentText><authorName>yiqz</authorName><authorID>142uyg</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6anym6<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494648408.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhhbd1u</commentID><commentText>[deleted]</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494585566.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhg86d5</commentID><commentText>I'm an econ major. I think the hardest classes would be the intro classes (designed to weed out students) because of how nitpicky Hamilton is. After that, you'll cruise until your upperclassmen years. Anything finance related will be tough. Be especially cautious with Duffee, he is a great professor but you'll have to put in a ton of work. 

Not much calculus is used other than the ocasional derivative in the core classes. If you take finance courses though you'll probably end up doing a lot of advanced math. 

Without a doubt take economics of fixed income instruments by Duffee. He only offers it once every two years so it should be available when you are a junior. I will tell you now that if I'm ever hiring and interview a Hopkins student who took that class and passed, they will probably get the job on the spot. </commentText><authorName>tercac</authorName><authorID>8utsv</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6amdcz<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494574876.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhg09tf</commentID><commentText>depends on where you at transferring from. If its something like comm college it will be night and day and you'll probably struggle to develop the mentality you need here during the first few months... At comm college I put in 0 effort and had a 4.0. At Hopkins my first few exams of freshman year I put my best effort and barely made C+s, and that was only after the curves</commentText><authorName>tercac</authorName><authorID>8utsv</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6aldos<comments /></submission><submission>6ajz9v<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494538925.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhf4as4</commentID><commentText>&gt; A non-specific, unverified threat of a bomb at the Homewood campus was called in this morning to Baltimore police. Johns Hopkins security has been searching academic buildings at Homewood where exams are scheduled. Nothing suspicious has been found to this point. 
&gt; 
&gt; We expect to confirm shortly that academic buildings have been checked. Please remain out of exam rooms for now. We will send additional confirmation soon, but expect 9 a.m. exams to begin at 10 a.m. The 2 p.m. exams will begin on time.


What a dumb delay tactic if it turns out to be a false alarm. That student could risk his entire academic career if caught.</commentText><authorName>Oangusa</authorName><authorID>7upm0</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494540758.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhf5qdc</commentID><commentText>Let's take a look at a few factors:

- Bomb threats are almost never real. Common sense dictates this as well: If a terrorist wanted to actually cause damage to people/places/things, then why give people a warning of it? Why not just blow them up? Sure, the threat is too great to ignore, and at least one bomb threat has resulted in an attack, but look at this article (https://www.inlander.com/Bloglander/archives/2015/04/10/idle-threats-expert-says-bomb-threats-are-pretty-much-always-duds):

&gt; In talking to a colleague from the ATFE, I asked him how many bomb threats he had responded to over his 30-plus year-career, where he had found a real bomb and he said, &#8220;Zero.&#8221; He has certainly discovered real bombs when called to the homes of bomb makers. He has found real and fake bombs when called by people who saw an odd-looking device on the ground, but again, real bombers bomb, they don&#8217;t make bomb threats.

- The timing. The timing is too perfect -- right before final exams, someone calls in a bomb threat. Really? But again, since it's a threat of a bomb, all JHU could do was take the threat seriously and scramble to resolve the situation as quickly and as safely as possible. </commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6ai43l<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494547736.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhfbybd</commentID><commentText>Mine was gone as soon as the car was unloaded</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494546376.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhfape0</commentID><commentText>There's nothing like that -- they should stay for a day or two to help you get settled.</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6a5r3y<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494378418.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhc3pvk</commentID><commentText>Studio 7 the Salon and Spa (800 N. Charles St)

Call tomorrow after 3 (410)528-7158 and I can book you an appointment. Women's haircuts start at $30, or $45 with a blowout. We do offer a student discount on Tuesday and Wednesday, as long as you mention it and have your student id. 

Edit: and if it's just a bang trim, it's $10</commentText><authorName>operadiva31</authorName><authorID>ywuzc</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494505073.0</commentCreated><commentID>dheoyga</commentID><commentText>Glad I could help you out today!!!</commentText><authorName>operadiva31</authorName><authorID>ywuzc</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494395194.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhcippl</commentID><commentText>I've gone to tenpachi in fells point and they're pretty good! Their express cut is about $20 and I think they're bang trimming is $7 </commentText><authorName>elementalseahorse</authorName><authorID>x7bk5</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6a01nf<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494299594.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhaofj9</commentID><commentText>I once heard him say that he graduated from JHU a while back (maybe the 70s? don't really remember). I've seen him around both with and without the PA system, which he did have last year. It used to be even louder.

Other than that, I don't know much about him either.</commentText><authorName>neerpoom</authorName><authorID>14rsm1</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494332169.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhbe7np</commentID><commentText>He's been around since my freshman year.. we just know him as preacher man</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>69vnwt<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494277063.0</commentCreated><commentID>dha5mkk</commentID><commentText>As opposed to ascent apartments?</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494267578.0</commentCreated><commentID>dha1bfm</commentID><commentText>There are apartments in that price range, but I would advise against trying to swing a car. Parking is atrocious near the DC campus unless you are willing to pay for a garage. You'd be much better off metroing or even biking.</commentText><authorName>ductape821</authorName><authorID>7bfj1</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494324985.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhb9bpw</commentID><commentText>try cross-posting this to /r/washingtondc </commentText><authorName>kalotypography</authorName><authorID>fq5iu</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494473796.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhe04ja</commentID><commentText>Lots of good neighborhoods in downtown DC at that budget--Columbia Heights, Petworth, and Shaw come to mind. All on Yellow/Green line but easily accessible to Dupont. You won't get a 1 bedroom in Dupont for $2000.</commentText><authorName>ac91</authorName><authorID>658hi</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>69sh69<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494222211.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh9bxt5</commentID><commentText>Political science major here. Usually no curves in any  of the classes. If anything, the curve will be the TA's or professor's unwillingness to hand out an "A." </commentText><authorName>prez_hamilton</authorName><authorID>wrh9v</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494207877.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh90jj5</commentID><commentText>Generally speaking, no. I've taken 5-6 poli sci and IS courses and none of them have been curved. </commentText><authorName>PolyatomicWeener</authorName><authorID>vfg0w</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>69pme2<comments><comment><commentCreated>1495107055.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhpgt51</commentID><commentText>I toured them a few months ago (I'm also an incoming grad student) and wasn't very impressed. Rooms were very old-looking, kind of scary honestly. Most of the apartments in the area (Charles and Blackstone, Jeffersonian) are like that. I would recommend just looking at the off-campus housing website and craigslist listings for Charles Village, Oakenshaw, Tuscany-Canterbury, and maybe Hampden. </commentText><authorName>a2z95</authorName><authorID>mdd34</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>69lq95<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494116360.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh7kqb0</commentID><commentText>DC: MARC train from Penn station. $7 each way with many trains each day. There is a bike car on the weekends.

Philly: Amtrak from Penn station. Not sure the cost but you can check on the website</commentText><authorName>mehuman</authorName><authorID>410j0</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>69febk<comments /></submission><submission>69ab9w<comments><comment><commentCreated>1494020210.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh5yczi</commentID><commentText>It's got a mix of all of those things. You can meet people in the library :')</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493974437.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh5ay4a</commentID><commentText>Yes to everything. </commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494023852.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh618fd</commentID><commentText>I don't know too much but most of the freshman couples from my year (currently a sophomore) are still together so that's pretty cool. I think if you're looking for hookups though they still happen at parties a lot, but I haven't really been a part of that so I can't say for sure, only from hearsay.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494040053.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh6eocr</commentID><commentText>There's kind of a big divide. I know several people from my class who have gotten married / are engaged or in a relationship, and several others who were on the other end of the spectrum. It really depends who you hang out with. </commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494144965.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh84pmx</commentID><commentText>So. I was very much into the hookup culture as a freshman. It is definitely a thing if you are looking for it. I think that is the main point of a frat. On the other side, I am now in a several year relationship. So you can do whatever you want. It is all there. Best place to meet people? Like everywhere, depends on what you are looking for. 1 night stand? go to a frat.  </commentText><authorName>RumandCola17</authorName><authorID>f7ytw</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494938984.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhm777y</commentID><commentText>The hookup scene is definitely a thing and very easy to do, but I also know many people in a relationship. I feel like it's pretty common to hook up, even my friends in a relationship have had a few hook ups before/in between relationships. You can really make it what you want!

Usually early college relationships/hookups happen at frat parties, when freshmen are out partying a lot. Sophomores &amp; upperclassmen don't usually go out as much. If a sophomore/upperclassman isn't still dating their freshman gf/bf and starts a new relationship, it's usually a friend/classmate/hookup-turned-serious. It gets progressively harder to meet new people as you get older, so try to meet as many people freshman year as possible!</commentText><authorName>nowayrose</authorName><authorID>zar17</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1495137842.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhpuasb</commentID><commentText>If you get involved with Greek life, hookup culture is prevalent. If you don't, relationships are more likely. Best places to meet people is at Brody (other than reading room), FFC, and at random events with free food that occur on campus. And it is a small school so try not to embarrass yourself esp in and around your department</commentText><authorName>iainttalkingvegan</authorName><authorID>1fyv95t</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>698wdo<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493947841.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh4o7bn</commentID><commentText>Most grad students stick with Hampden, and some try to avoid Charles Village due to the undergrad population there. You'll find sturdy rowhomes in Hampden with about $1000-$1200 monthly rent. </commentText><authorName>amnnn</authorName><authorID>bwl9i</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493957683.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh4xjqx</commentID><commentText>If you pick Hampden or Abell, I'd suggest getting a bike </commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494016676.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh5vzsj</commentID><commentText>I'm happy in Tuscany-Canterbury. It is relatively safe, a few blocks to campus, and pretty quiet. Be careful about noise if looking in Charles Village-a friend lives near a frat house and has been pretty miserable all year due to noise from the parties they throw. </commentText><authorName>jisa</authorName><authorID>7w2kf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493966067.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh54swl</commentID><commentText>What about Oakenshaw? Someone is renting out their entire third floor on the corner of Calvert and Homewood and it seems like a good deal--not having a roommate but not living entirely alone, either.</commentText><authorName>a2z95</authorName><authorID>mdd34</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>692i6c<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493876422.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh3enkd</commentID><commentText>Why would you do CS, BME, AND med school? </commentText><authorName>coloradoforests1701</authorName><authorID>yle56</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493879882.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh3hg99</commentID><commentText>My best friend was a BME/CS double major, and is going to med school this fall. Honestly, if you like your classes and your major, then school will be much more doable. Difficulty is dependent on the individual person, so ymmv.

If you're set on medical school, just do a major you enjoy. (I know current med school students who were IS, mechE, history majors from hopkins, so just don't waste your time one something you don't wanna do for the next 4 years.)</commentText><authorName>MRturnip</authorName><authorID>7l1ik</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6920ta<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493893738.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh3slzo</commentID><commentText>Don't take Gen Physics, take the courses offered by the physics department for physics majors. The intro sequence is: Classical Mechanics (Fall) and E&amp;M (Spring). They're a lot more rigorous and you'll get to know the other physics majors in your year</commentText><authorName>mijcr</authorName><authorID>s8ym0</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493898543.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh3w64o</commentID><commentText>JHU Physics major here. Also heavily involved as a department liaison with students. If you plan to be a physics major, I highly recommend that you do NOT skip the first year courses. (These would be Classical Mechanics I and E&amp;M 1). Yes, you will see topics covered in your AP physics courses, but unless you have an extremely good grasp of multivariable calculus already, this physics - especially E&amp;M - will be tough.

Also: the sophomore course you would be taking, Special Relativity and Waves, is extremely difficult without basic Differential Equations or Linear Algebra. 

There is a reason only 1-2 majors every year skip these classes, and it's because they have background in both math and physics that makes this option better for them.

I was in a very similar situation to you, decided not to skip the courses, and am very glad I did. If you have any other questions, feel free to message me!</commentText><authorName>Tantalus2102</authorName><authorID>137f60</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493866663.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh35jmj</commentID><commentText>Not a physics major, but I retook physics here after getting 5s for AP Physics C and the only new thing I learned was Bernoulli's principle; everything else was review. Not sure of the difference between the generic Physics 1 and physics majors Physics 1, but I kinda regret taking it again and wouldn't if I could redo freshman year</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493878964.0</commentCreated><commentID>dh3gqit</commentID><commentText>I think if you're certain that your school had a very good AP Physics C course, then you should be fine skipping it. However, I don't think a 5 on the AP exam is indicative of having learned the material fully, since I definitely know that people who left half the exam blank my year got a 5. But if you're confident in your physics ability, skipping it might be okay. I do believe you have to talk to the department about it though.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>68h78h<comments /></submission><submission>67zozi<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493443859.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgvuh66</commentID><commentText>I have not, but:

"Can I defer my enrollment?
In some cases, students are permitted to defer their enrollment for up to two years to pursue a travel, work, or family experience that does not include study at another academic institution for credit.
Deferrals are considered on an individual basis and must be requested in writing from the Dean of Undergraduate Admissions. To request a deferral, you must submit your Reply Form, enrollment deposit, and a letter detailing your plans by the enrollment deposit deadline.
Students accepted as transfer students to Johns Hopkins are not typically granted admission deferrals."</commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493449781.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgvyqpe</commentID><commentText>No experience but based on what the guy above posted, note that it's on a "cast by case basis". So you're not *telling* them you're taking a gap year, you're *requesting* it. If they say no then you either have to start or drop out. 

The best thing to do is just call the admissions office...they'll know or get you to the person who can tell you with 100% certainty what their policy is. I suspect they're liberal about it if you have a reason...so if you're gonna be sitting around watching netflix then say something more legitimate...</commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493450927.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgvzjlw</commentID><commentText>Thanks for your replies - can I ask how much the enrollment deposit is? </commentText><authorName>cosmos3</authorName><authorID>114zx5</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>67or03<comments /></submission><submission>67l1s2<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493208734.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgrf86j</commentID><commentText>You're in luck because it's spring fair weekend. Go stop by the beer garden, and check out the Mason quad where all the random local vendors are. 

Check out Gilman hall, it's pretty nice. The Brody learning commons also, I think they let visitors in. 

If you're doing it all online then you don't really need to learn much about the campus...Just enjoy the spring fair activities </commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493668791.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgzcniv</commentID><commentText>I suspect there is nothing to visit at APL. first, it's a good bit out of Baltimore, and second, it's not really open to the public</commentText><authorName>jwink3101</authorName><authorID>6asud</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>67c1tf<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493198197.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgr76ns</commentID><commentText>Are you speaking about the EPP? If so, they don't offer MSE online, it's MS. I have read varied reviews online I will sum it up here. 

Internet hear-say: 

- Some people say the program is running in easy mode because they know a lot of people who do it are fully employed and don't have much time. 
- Some have said that it's a decent program and you will get a education. 
- Some say since the degree earned is not the same, employers discount the degree. And don't look at it as a worthwhile education. Also, JHU lacks connection with the high-tech world, sadly Google and Microsoft are rarely there apparently (this is what I have read and take with pile of salt) 
- Some have said that the program is way too expensive for what it's worth and instead of spending money, people should try to get their employers to pay for it since JHU is not as highly ranked in CS and engineering. I have heard many people say that Georgia Tech is better and cheaper ($7,000 for the whole degree) but the program is really hard and could take longer to complete.

My opinion:

I am in the same boat, I am looking for their CS program and am conflicted between the dirt cheap price of Georgia Tech VS high price of JHU. Google and other companies continuously hire from Georgia Tech, while JHU is mostly defense contractors looking for programmers and engineers for cheap. And their programs are mostly applied knowledge or vocational vs theoretical and rigorous. Lately I have been debating bridging from their online CS program to a PhD at a top 10 universities in the world. But the program is terminal and people have managed to bridge to a PhD, but it's very rare. I haven't found any alumni page or anything so I can ask them about the question that is bothering you too...so far mixed reviews is what I have had. If you find more info...please share. 

Note: I'll tag /u/nah_you_good in case what I have typed helps him/her. </commentText><authorName>_MadScientist_</authorName><authorID>e6bw7</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493118482.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgpp519</commentID><commentText>I've got the same question as you. I've got 0 experience with it and don't know anyone who has. How's the Penn program look?</commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>66zcw0<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492951037.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgmptve</commentID><commentText>I'll rattle off some of the pros of being a JHU ECE. I You will never worry about not being able to register for a class, as class sizes are pretty small. You'll probably get to know everyone in your class by the end of your second year. If you want to double in CS that's pretty easy to do, and a lot of ECE students do it. Our signal processing classes/research is world class. The JHU Applied Physics Lab, where many Hopkins ECE students intern and work, is world class. If you want to do research it's super easy to meet with professors (aside from a select few) and get started here, even as a freshman. We have a lounge with free coffee/printing. 

However, I will admit there is little to no help given by the department when it comes to providing internships/job opportunities. This is slightly due to faculty's preference for students to work in their labs over the summer instead, but it's mostly because they don't really care what underclassmen do. There is a career fair every semester (not hosted by ece) but it is geared towards internships in software, defense contractors, or consulting.&#160;

There are also serious flaws with the ECE curriculum here but there are some steps being taken to fix that (kind of). I personally feel like this isn't too big an issue because there is still a great amount of flexibility when it comes to choosing courses.&#160;

Your best bet is to speak to upperclassmen about their experiences in this (and other) departments, but you will honestly be fine with whatever major your choose in the end. </commentText><authorName>EpicCelloMan54</authorName><authorID>bqbhi</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>66x974<comments><comment><commentCreated>1493111381.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgpjpwf</commentID><commentText>Haven't taken language and mind or forensic psych, but I can comment on intro psych and positive psych!

1) Intro psych prof is drigotas- 400 person lecture, no homework/reading, grading is on a point based scale (have to get x number of points out of 400 to get an A), very easy in comparison to other courses at hopkins. Really just have to listen to lecture and memorize notes. He used to base his tests off of backtests, but when i took it he'd changed up the exam so it was different. It's an easy B, but you'll have to work to make sure you know the lectures well enough to score an A (when there's 40 q's on the exam, missing 5 q's is already an 88%) Shouldn't be too hard to get into since it's 400 ppl (depending on what year you are tho it might be)

3) Positive psych - super fun and interesting class! Highly recommend, esp during a hard science heavy semester. Homework is primarily journal entries that take maybe ~1 hr/week and really short readings. 2 multiple choice exams that are memorization of lecture notes. A little bit disorganized but the prof is super nice and you get to do a lot of self reflection which is nice. Might be more difficult to get into, since it's only like a 60 person class. I registered for it as a junior and got in.
</commentText><authorName>sincerelypicasso</authorName><authorID>z7bws</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>66w9ov<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492901923.0</commentCreated><commentID>dglqz8o</commentID><commentText>The second schedule is definitely do-able. Get those H/S reqs out of the way early; I recommend taking Psych if you want something easy and interesting. FYI, you definitely won't get into computer ethics: I'm a rising senior and I have tried registering for it for 6 semesters now and just now succeeded in enrolling. </commentText><authorName>nkrishn9</authorName><authorID>x56tv</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492927884.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgma19y</commentID><commentText>You can't get computer ethics as a freshman, but other than that all those classes are a breeze so definitely doable! Also, my boyfriend and I may also be graduating with CS in 3 years and it is more difficult than it appears if you don't take a solid number of CS courses in your freshman year&#8212;they all get too difficult after that. What other APs/IBs do you have that have placed you out of things? </commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>66f6ge<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492687421.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi19w5</commentID><commentText>Positive: chicken parm at Uni Mini</commentText><authorName>hungryhungryhippooo</authorName><authorID>86z7y</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492691549.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi42x4</commentID><commentText>Negative: no student union so people socialize in the library (Brody), which isn't ideal.

Positive: Baltimore is better than I thought. Never really felt unsafe, lots of good restaurants, and bars are fun when you turn 21.</commentText><authorName>hongkongdryclean</authorName><authorID>54pqo</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492692024.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi4dcc</commentID><commentText>administration can be a pain in the ass, but I can't compare it to other schools </commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492730248.0</commentCreated><commentID>dginrct</commentID><commentText>(Pro) It's not hard to make friends and join clubs, I highly recommend it. Some host occasional parties, others give you a place to play games and chill with a group of people.

The menu changes week to week/day to day. Something great pops out once in a while. Nolans has pretty good food.
...........................................................................................

(Cons) FFC and Charles Market Meal in a Minute (The only places where your freshmen meal swipes are used) food is generally crappy, but tolerable/good some weeks. There are plenty of other places around for a cost, but for lunch in between classes, you will go to the FFC most days.

.........................................................................................

(Word of Warning) AMR's are generally way more social than Wolman/McCoy. Some floors on Wolman are more social than others. You may be best friends with your roommate, or you may barely talk to them. Everyone is running on their own schedule, and everyone is doing something. 


</commentText><authorName>IDKWhoitis</authorName><authorID>j7iqk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492690697.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi3jgo</commentID><commentText>Brody cafe has fire dirty chai lattes, 10/10 would recommend</commentText><authorName>seniorhoward</authorName><authorID>o9ft4</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492697270.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi73ge</commentID><commentText>Hey :) if you end up committing, hit me up! I'm going there in the fall too</commentText><authorName>TheAsianIsGamin</authorName><authorID>eezfl</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492739095.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgiw1kz</commentID><commentText>food on campus is meh. Food off campus is close by though.</commentText><authorName>trashacount12345</authorName><authorID>3w2ki</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492769637.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgjm7le</commentID><commentText>Tell us your thoughts, as well as your other options. Then we can provide a bit more contextually-relevant advice. </commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493467763.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgwbec6</commentID><commentText>Meh, JHU is filled with a bunch of rich entitled spawns, so of course there will be something to complain about.  

Like forget the fact that you fucking go to I e of the top universities in the entire world that has billions of dollars in endowments, let's focus on the fact that the frat parties suck.....lol.  you'll realize later 10 years from now no one ever gives a shit about or remembers the partying.  </commentText><authorName>Jhuacehole</authorName><authorID>17hzma</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492691831.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi492c</commentID><commentText>I'd tell you, but it would exceed the character limit. </commentText><authorName>SurpriseElephant</authorName><authorID>dhkeo</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492696470.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgi6qm5</commentID><commentText>Too many things to list.</commentText><authorName>axelrodsmoke</authorName><authorID>14bay7</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>666pak<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492633662.0</commentCreated><commentID>dggqi3x</commentID><commentText>[deleted]</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1493115758.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgpn37v</commentID><commentText>Hmmm I'm not really sure why everyone is saying to wait to take lab. Orgo with lab in the summer was/is doable. I did orgo 1 and 2 with the 3 credit lab last summer. Lab was very straight forward. Pretty sure the average was an A/A-. Lectka was awesome.</commentText><authorName>Antique_Healbot</authorName><authorID>woigv</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>664e2v<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492587525.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgg06ej</commentID><commentText>&gt; John Hopkins

I seriously didn't think I'd have to pull out this novelty account in /r/JHU of all places but...

It's John**s** Hopkins.</commentText><authorName>YouForgotTheS</authorName><authorID>sj3s9</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492567127.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgfhzcc</commentID><commentText>[deleted]</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492603741.0</commentCreated><commentID>dggdma5</commentID><commentText>Move into a row house with parking?

Seriously though, why do you really even need a car? Are you that lazy?</commentText><authorName>MyTribeCalledQuest</authorName><authorID>4omi4</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6611y2<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492570576.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgfl6s4</commentID><commentText>I liked the smaller size of the university vs a large public university. But look into the research opportunities at both school too. The opportunity to join a research lab at Hopkins was a huge plus for me. Because it's a smaller school, but there are still so many professors/faculty doing research (particularly with the medical school too), there are a lot of places to look to join labs (whether you do it for credit or for pay, it's still great for your resume when applying to grad school). I ended up joining a lab at the medical school as a research assistant toward the end dof my freshman year and continued working there all the way through senior year. So if you're interested in combining EE and/or CS with medical/life sciences research, there will be plenty of labs to join at Hopkins even as an undergrad. It'll help you see what grad school is like in terms of the research and possibly get your name on some publications too.

That said, Georgia Tech is still a great school, particularly for EE/CS. For those fields, both schools will bring name value.</commentText><authorName>hungryhungryhippooo</authorName><authorID>86z7y</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492570806.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgfleij</commentID><commentText>&gt; Nevertheless, there is a lot of research and cool things, as well as individualized attention at Hopkins, so I was thinking of EE/CS or EE and Neuroscience to then go into grad school in BME. 

If you'r interest is in Neuro, Hopkins is a very good choice. If you're thinking you'd rather go get a job after college (which i usually recommend to engineers rather then go straight into a PhD) Tech will give you a broad set of non-medical opportunities. Hopkins is very high up there in neuroscience though. Lot's of large discoveries happened here, and there are a number of cool labs that could use an engineer's perspective. </commentText><authorName>trashacount12345</authorName><authorID>3w2ki</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492637168.0</commentCreated><commentID>dggsusf</commentID><commentText>Research is the big one, but the high ranking overall and strong brand recognition makes a Hopkins degree pretty valuable. I haven't run into anyone professionally that hadn't heard of/wasn't impressed when I mentioned I went to Hopkins. Although I studied engineering, I didn't go directly into my field, so if you know you want to make a career of your major, than a higher ranked program is a better choice, but if you are less sure, a degree with recognition and respect across every industry is pretty valuable</commentText><authorName>my_gamertag_wastaken</authorName><authorID>pb85b</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492656967.0</commentCreated><commentID>dghb5z3</commentID><commentText>I'm a CS major here. One of the biggest reasons I chose Hopkins however was actually not for their CS program, but for their flexibility in schedule because there's no required core classes and I really wanted to do a double major in Writing Seminars (the other big reason I chose Hopkins, since their writing program is so strong). This might not be helpful for you then, but I personally think our CS program is really strong and is only continuing to get stronger. The problem is that it's not scaling to the number of students who are joining the major, so it's kind of annoying to get into classes&#8212;something you might want to be aware of.

Additionally, for CS in particular, Google has recently really upped their recruiting here, so I think they're into us :D

If you're considering a double major, I would assume that Hopkins is a better place to go, especially because there are a lot of opportunities to do research here in bio/medicine-related topics with CS.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492551976.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgf49eu</commentID><commentText>I was in a similar position as you with the choice to go to a public institution with a top 5 ranked CS program vs Hopkins. Simply put it's the perks of being a private institution: the attention you get with smaller class sizes, the opportunities, less competition, more interesting classes, and the Hopkins name as well. 

But your impression of wherever you fit the best is most important. Location and cost are important too. Research at Hopkins drew me in as well. </commentText><authorName>curious_neuron</authorName><authorID>wqqfh</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492559639.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgfawj5</commentID><commentText>Not a CS major but from experience at networking/social events the name of Hopkins will carry much more weight </commentText><authorName>tercac</authorName><authorID>8utsv</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492547398.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgf16si</commentID><commentText>BME is kind of overrated. That's why I'm going to do Comp Sci at JHU. Georgia Tech is very well known for it's Comp sci though, so you could go there.</commentText><authorName>ahowe444</authorName><authorID>g8dsb</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>65so0f<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492435238.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgd5k8e</commentID><commentText>http://krieger.jhu.edu/ewp/courses/fall-courses/

Unfortunately this says the topics for Fall 2017's Expos courses won't be posted until late June... So you would have to just sign up for something that has a convenient time for you and then check back to see if the topic works for you. It's shitty but that's the way they've decided to do it for some reason.</commentText><authorName>axelrodsmoke</authorName><authorID>14bay7</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492434600.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgd58t7</commentID><commentText>As far as I know, they haven't finalized the classes for next year. That should be done soon, I imagine by the end of the month. </commentText><authorName>philobug</authorName><authorID>46pmr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492581655.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgfvhc2</commentID><commentText>If you want more information about the TAs there's the teacher course evaluations which are fairly reliable:

https://studentaffairs.jhu.edu/registrar/faculty-staff/course-evaluations/

You can control+f the TA's name for different semesters to see their rating and other feedback. The TA's switch around from year to year so you may not be able to find feedback for all the TAs that you're interested in but odds are some of them have probably taught within the last year or two.</commentText><authorName>StrangeLoner</authorName><authorID>7bt05</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6572fk<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492206317.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg955ez</commentID><commentText>You should post this in /r/Baltimore and /r/Maryland. Also, I wouldn't say "kiddos" in the title, it made me question the seriousness of your survey.</commentText><authorName>falynw</authorName><authorID>q1evv</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>652ez4<comments><comment><commentCreated>1492080408.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg70wwi</commentID><commentText>I know for BMEs at least, a math minor just entails taking one more 300 level class and yer done. Not sure how much math ChemBEs take (too lazy to google it) but it probably isn't that much more to get the minor and then decide if you want the major. You don't need to declare either one up until like before you register to graduate, so you'll have time if you want to back out.</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492143906.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg860b2</commentID><commentText>I doubled in economics and applied math but I know people who did BME / AMS etc. I think Applied Math is more beneficial than pure maths as pure maths will force you to take things like Real / Complex Analysis, Algebra, and Measure Theory which are just not useful outside of upper level maths or specific graduate programs in fields like economics. I took a few of these courses (Real Analysis, Complex Analysis, etc.) and really unless you are super into math it's just not a good time. The Applied Math department seems to strike a better balance and people are more fun. Additionally, I think employers prefer the Applied Math / Statistics over Pure Math, but that's just a minor point. Also Applied Math will give you more experience with tools like R / MATLAB which are more useful skills than Real Analysis in general. It really comes down to what you are interested in though, and if you do well in either it will certainly be fine. </commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492133958.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg7wsgx</commentID><commentText>Personally, I think it is very important that you ask and answer this question "What classes am I interested in and will they help me achieve my goal(s) after undergrad?"
If a double major's requirements are difficult to meet, you can always take the math classes you want. No one really cares about the name of your major. They care more about your individual skills and knowledge. This is true for industry, med school, law school, and grad school. </commentText><authorName>DottedGlass</authorName><authorID>zryea</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492517740.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgeoork</commentID><commentText>You should do both</commentText><authorName>Pokerdude02052</authorName><authorID>127cxs</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492121096.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg7l0v2</commentID><commentText>Pure math is for Nazis.</commentText><authorName>Yawehg</authorName><authorID>6nksr</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>64vswd<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491999680.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg5gnt4</commentID><commentText>Def possible. I would say EE + Neuro is a stronger combination than BME (if you're already set on neuroengineering)</commentText><authorName>n3ur0n</authorName><authorID>hsm1k</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492040196.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg616rc</commentID><commentText>possible but knowing people that have done both, it's going to be a very difficult road</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492001019.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg5hexh</commentID><commentText>I wouldn't do Neuroscience and instead do CS. Prosthetics and BCI mainly deal with signal processing and software/hardware engineering. In fact, many of the Grad students working on those are actually EE/CE majors. </commentText><authorName>curious_neuron</authorName><authorID>wqqfh</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492004411.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg5j68c</commentID><commentText>One other thing I forgot to add. I had heard going to Hopkins for my undergrad will make it possible for me to get a BME masters in 5 years even if I do another type of engineering for undergrad. Is that a true statement? And is it very difficult to get accepted to that type of program?</commentText><authorName>vishmanx</authorName><authorID>xs51y</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492144241.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg86b4a</commentID><commentText>You might want to consider CS / CE as well. I have no experience in the field but I feel like EE is getting antiquated. </commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492292753.0</commentCreated><commentID>dganmhi</commentID><commentText>So would be possible to do EE/CS in four years at Hopkins? Also, a lot of you are saying do something other than Neuro but the reason I want to do neuro is I'm unsure on what I want to do yet. I know I want engineering in undergrad, but I am considering med school later. I know it'll be hard to keep a good GPA but both really fascinate me, so I'm having a tough time deciding.</commentText><authorName>vishmanx</authorName><authorID>xs51y</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>64nzig<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491907139.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg3q7zk</commentID><commentText>I think people tend to have the best experience in Wolman. The whole roommate deal sounds like you just may have gotten someone who wasn't very interested. I had two roommates freshman year and I am good friends with one and have basically forgotten the other.

A dining dollar is virtual money you can spend at certain Hopkins dining facilities that don't take meal swipes. I'm sure you'll discover those when you actually get here.</commentText><authorName>jz911</authorName><authorID>4nkty</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491948630.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg4as3q</commentID><commentText>Since we're all drawing mostly from personal experience, I have to mention that the AMRs were hands-down the best possible option my freshman year.

The AMRs had consistently strong communities across floors and houses, whereas Wolman and McCoy tended to be a crapshoot. Buildings A/B were basically the deadlands.


That's all anecdotal, but a strong objective argument for AMR is its proximity to the FFC, the freshman quad, and campus in general. There's something cool about actually living on campus, and freshman year is your only chance to do it at JHU.

In the end though, don't stress about it. College isn't like boarding high school, there's a million places to meet people and make friends and the dorm is just one of them. If you end up with a roommate you don't love, you'll still be finding friends during orientation, at activities, in class, and in places you don't expect.

There's no way to optimize your collegiate social life, you've got to just give yourself up to it.</commentText><authorName>Yawehg</authorName><authorID>6nksr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491913753.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg3utj6</commentID><commentText>I don't think I've heard anyone complain about their experience in Wolman. The layout of the dorm (all the rooms sort of surround a common room) seems more conducive to social interaction, and I've heard that the RAs in Wolman typically do a good job of bringing their floor together. AMR I/II are definitely traditional, and I didn't want to do the communal bathroom thing, but if your reservation is based on the fact that your high school roommates weren't sociable, don't expect the opposite. Roommates are chosen at random unless you specifically pair up with another person, but I would say that bad roommates are on the rarer side. 
All of my friends who lived in Building B LOVED their experience and have stayed friends with their dorm mates up until now (senior year).  
It's pretty hard to get a single room unless you have special accommodations, so if I were you, I'd expect to be put in a double. 
Here's my ranking of dorms:
(1) Wolman, (2) The Buildings, (3) AMR I/II</commentText><authorName>leafwatcher</authorName><authorID>12j2lp</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491966978.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg4rck4</commentID><commentText>As someone in the AMRS right not, make sure you consider that I and II don't have central air conditioning (all other dorms do). This can make for some VERY uncomfortable conditions at the beginning and end of the year if you're not prepared</commentText><authorName>HydraXBaron</authorName><authorID>65pur</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492055327.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg6ftdd</commentID><commentText>Wolman for sure, as an AMR II resident it kind of sucked unless you really don't care about no AC, communal showers, low quality rooms, etc.</commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492518743.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgepcge</commentID><commentText>DONT DO WOLMAN
DO AMR II
FRIENDS FOREVER </commentText><authorName>Pokerdude02052</authorName><authorID>127cxs</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>64nid8<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491904048.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg3nnl9</commentID><commentText>r/cscareerquestions</commentText><authorName>longestPath</authorName><authorID>8xpsz</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491904009.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg3nmev</commentID><commentText>CS depends a lot more on your portfolio, coding skills, and experience than on your GPA. A 3.0 is fine if you can interview well. Worse than that isn't a deal breaker, but then you'd need to lean on your portfolio more. </commentText><authorName>knockoutn336</authorName><authorID>8s4mr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491909268.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg3rvch</commentID><commentText>Anything above 3.0 with a good resume will get you interviews. More prestigious companies like Google, Facebook, Dropbox would want to see 3.5+ but also give holistic consideration to your resume. Companies also take into account the courses you took and their difficulty.</commentText><authorName>curious_neuron</authorName><authorID>wqqfh</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>64ahr3<comments /></submission><submission>642gmt<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491631377.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfz3tf6</commentID><commentText>I want more Ron Daniels fan fic</commentText><authorName>overlapt</authorName><authorID>znk0r</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491638391.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfz8rsp</commentID><commentText>For all you haters, this is a copypasta: https://www.reddit.com/r/copypasta/comments/47crtk/the_supermarket_encounter/</commentText><authorName>sltnlght</authorName><authorID>j6e3i</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491631326.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfz3s4d</commentID><commentText>Did he also tell you how many times he's seen Led Zeppelin in concert. If so I don't think that was Ron Daniels </commentText><authorName>pomeronion</authorName><authorID>11qpto</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491637678.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfz8a06</commentID><commentText>I don't think that was Ron Daniels...</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63xx05<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491576965.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfy2i8t</commentID><commentText>I suspect it depends on the professor, but just remember it's a semester-long class crammed into 4 weeks. That has to include times for tests too, so you're looking at final + study days, and a midterm or 2 + study days, so the actual class time is super condensed. 


When I took it I believe classes were 1.5ish hours. The good thing is they basically have a microphone and lecture on a virtual whiteboard. So you can watch the replays of it later for efficient studying, or if you miss it. 

The hard thing is they still make sure you know all the material that they normally reach over 9 weeks, so you'll have homework every other day probably. You'll also need to watch the class, then spend a couple of hours learning the concepts to ensure you have a good mastery. It's graded as harshly as a standard Hopkins math class, or maybe a bit easier but not much. 

It's a good environment for getting a much better understanding of Lin alg, and the classes are smaller so you can ask questions and contact the professor directly. </commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491587470.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfy668y</commentID><commentText>I took Differential Equations online a couple summers back and would highly recommend it. Actually I would recommend taking any course online.

My DiffEQ course was taught by a couple of graduate students, who I felt were very effective at teaching the material and were also good at communicating with students in general. For example they were pretty lenient with credit on homeworks and exams, and were understanding about work turned in late. If grad students are teaching Lin Alg, I say go for it for sure. If not then see who's teaching during the school year and compare. 

The biggest advantage of an online class is the online lectures. You can pause/rewind anytime you want and can watch them at your leisure. If you show up to lecture it's easy to ask questions and have a discussion on the online board. 

The only thing Im unsure about is how condensed the teaching might have to be in order to cover all the material, but during the summer you'll probably have only like two or three classes/job to worry about so it's pretty hard to get behind.

Hope this helps.</commentText><authorName>EpicCelloMan54</authorName><authorID>bqbhi</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63mzpo<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491444659.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfvft44</commentID><commentText>Just remember to use jh.edu instead of JHU.edu and it usually works for me. </commentText><authorName>Anthrax175</authorName><authorID>emibb</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63m401<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491453502.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfvoas9</commentID><commentText>60 days is actually a lot of time.  Many cities (DC, NY) are only 30 days (this is favorable to tenants -- they can give as little as 30 days notice to their landlords).  Lots of buildings have pretty near instant availability -- i.e. you can move into an apartment soon after you view it.  

Since you're coming from abroad, I'd recommend finding an airbnb/short-term sublet and look for housing in person when you arrive.  You can also browse Craigslist to find people subletting a room in a row house/apartment or people looking to for someone to sign onto a lease.  If you choose the Craigslist route (I have from abroad - worked out well), definitely ask your prospective roommates to conduct a Skype tour of the apartment.
</commentText><authorName>hopelepoh</authorName><authorID>9vxtm</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63eayx<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491352049.0</commentCreated><commentID>dftkpaq</commentID><commentText>The professors I had for my online classes were just as accessible as the classes I took at the APL, and just as accessible as any of my undergraduate professors. They all responded in a timely fashion and all had adobe connect office hours once a week.</commentText><authorName>maxximillian</authorName><authorID>51tvh</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491382557.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfubzcx</commentID><commentText>[deleted]</commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63cad4<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491351238.0</commentCreated><commentID>dftjxwm</commentID><commentText>I don't have any experience with the AMS or CS minors, so I can't comment on linear algebra. My sophomore fall I took Biochemistry, Process Analysis (couldn't take it freshman year at the time), Thermo, and Transport 1. It was manageable though I had to sacrifice a lot of free time. Adding another class with a good amount of work (intermediate or LA) would be okay, but you'll be doing schoolwork pretty much 24/7. </commentText><authorName>SurpriseElephant</authorName><authorID>dhkeo</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491384348.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfudikq</commentID><commentText>I also do not have any experience with the AMS or CS courses; however, from what I've heard, intermediate programming takes up a lot of your time. During my Soph Fall, I took Anthropology, Psych, Thermo, Biochem and it was extremely handleable. In regards to Bevan's teaching, it is true that he is not a great teacher. However, his exam problems are pretty fair and predictable (you also get a cheat sheet); and the curve he has at the end of the class is generous. As far as your class schedule, I would recommend sticking with what you have: Thermo, Intermediate, Biochem, Lin Alg. Transport 1 should be with Frechette in the Fall and KK in the Spring. I've heard that Frechette is a little easier, but KK is a great lecturer/teacher. I would stick with Thermo, since the person who teaches Thermo in the spring is pretty disorganized. With the classes above, I think you'll definitely be able to handle the workload, but it may end up being an extremely busy semester for you.</commentText><authorName>yiqz</authorName><authorID>142uyg</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1492350043.0</commentCreated><commentID>dgbqtso</commentID><commentText>Bevan is the better of the thermo professors. And you definitely want to be taking transport with KK in the spring. Lin alg you don't need for the major - why are you taking it? Intermediate takes a lot of time but as long as you have time its pretty manageable.

All in all, this is a pretty heavy courseload, tbh. If you can do all of this and have time for other stuff, go ahead. But really keep in mind how important balance is - you want to have time to wind down and do extracurriculars and stuff like that. 

Edit: sorry just read the math minor part. </commentText><authorName>the_itchy_melon</authorName><authorID>zr9mk</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63bcyr<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491300872.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsrmsj</commentID><commentText>3 in one room</commentText><authorName>GoSh4rks</authorName><authorID>dm0ss</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63adav<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491291549.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsjvbd</commentID><commentText>no i think it's mandatory to live on campus</commentText><authorName>bluuuu34343</authorName><authorID>139u8t</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491308715.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsxe7e</commentID><commentText>To be completely honest, it's what you make it. If your friend ended up in McCoy with good friends and good roommates, they'll be fine. If not, get ready for a year of hell. Bad roommates at Commons is definitely a fuckton more tolerable than bad roommates in McCool. </commentText><authorName>sale2098</authorName><authorID>14tke0</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491343813.0</commentCreated><commentID>dftdd8v</commentID><commentText>How much time are you really going to spend in your room anyway? Sleeping, *some* studying, *some* socializing, *maybe some* cooking?

I was slated for McCoy heading into my sophomore year, whereas all of my friends except my roommate had Charles Commons or Homewood. I was furious and saddened that a random system had given me such a supposedly terrible place. 

I ended up spending the majority of my time at the library, my fraternity house, my friends' places in other buildings, the gym...basically used my dorm to sleep, and definitely didn't sleep there every night. 

Don't worry about it. </commentText><authorID>none</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>63a3cm<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491294050.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfslymm</commentID><commentText>When I was a sophomore I lived in commons and did the 7 swipes a week with dining dollars. Ate dinners at commons and used dining dollars at the market for stuff to make breakfasts and lunches. </commentText><authorName>sprintingthadistance</authorName><authorID>6vacz</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491297531.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsou4o</commentID><commentText>Swipes work in Nolans as well for sophomores &amp; up. I usually eat a lot/swiped friends in to FFC so I had the unlimited but could've gotten away with 19 a week easily imo</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491291489.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsjtn9</commentID><commentText>i'm living in commons next year too and i've heard the all dining dollar plan is the way to go but I guess it depends on how often/how much you eat</commentText><authorName>bluuuu34343</authorName><authorID>139u8t</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491303903.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsu22k</commentID><commentText>Living in Commons rn with unlimited and I wish I got 14 swipes/week instead since I'm too lazy to walk to the FFC for breakfast and I never go to late night </commentText><authorName>kalotypography</authorName><authorID>fq5iu</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491708633.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg093m5</commentID><commentText>the all dining dollar plan is more economical because you can add dining dollars using real money at a 1:1 ratio (any meal plan i think you can do that) but me and my friends who live in commons now did the math and the dining dollar plan is better unless you eat at the FFC /Nolans like 5 or 6 times a day</commentText><authorName>forrnaldehyde</authorName><authorID>xptmx</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>639zwz<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491288440.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfshe3v</commentID><commentText>Take Dev Bio Lab. You get to see cooler stuff while in Genetics Lab if it decides to rain one day all your planaria die and you have no data.

TBF, this was when I took it 5 years ago, so your mileage may vary.</commentText><authorName>KoreanEdelweiss</authorName><authorID>7jv90</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491299020.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfsq2wg</commentID><commentText>Take Dev Bio Lab. I had to take Genetics lab because I didn't want to double up on labs, but we were basically growing yeast the entire time. I think we also crossed some microscopic worms? But in Dev Bio, you get to grow a chick from what I remember. I will say that I think Genetics lab had the better curve/easier grading. 

I graduated in 2015, however, so things might have changed over the 2/3 years.</commentText><authorName>palmtreesh526</authorName><authorID>7o37p</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>632v9q<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491272224.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfs3l1k</commentID><commentText>I love the Japanese department. It's really tough though so be prepared to work on it (either language actually) for multiple hours a day. I was the same and had no prior experience with Japanese and failed/dropped out by the end of my first semester. 

That being said.....still love the Japanese department. They were super nice and helpful while I was struggling. They want you to become masters of the language. </commentText><authorName>SchrodingersSexLife</authorName><authorID>bd46q</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>630lob<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491194603.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfqowde</commentID><commentText>Adding onto what the other person said - you benefit from being inside of a real city, and the weather is nicer than Cornell. Outside of class you find that little things like this really matter when you live in a place for four years.</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491189447.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfql1t9</commentID><commentText>Hopkins is what you make of it. 

One thing I really love is the proximity to DC, New York, and Philadelphia. I'm a freshman and this year alone I've gone up to DC probably 5 times and New York twice. It's relatively cheap to do so too (MARC train tickets to DC are $8). 

People here like to complain about being stressed and busy all the time and while it can be true, I feel like it's a bit exaggerated. People like to make memes/rag on the school all the time saying how much they hate it but I love self-deprecating humor so maybe I'm biased (just check out the hopkins meme page). Overall I feel like students do like it here. 

The food at Cornell is probs way better if that matters to you. There's not a lot of options in Baltimore imo, but I came from California with great food so idk. 

There's a ton of clubs and social activism events on campus. One thing I really love is the activist/volunteering done on campus. I tutor a local Baltimore student and am part of a homelessness awareness club. Being in Baltimore really changed my perspective on a lot of issues like this and I don't think a place like Cornell could have done the same. 

Tons of people here do research too, if you're into that. Mostly STEM, but I know some humanities ppl that do it too. I myself have had a lot of cool experiences. I got to go to see a talk by Justice Sotomayer in DC, Bernie Sanders came to our school to speak, I went white water kayaking, I got my own radio show, and I got to go to the Women's March in DC. 

I myself don't really party but it's definitely available if you want it. Mostly frats/sororities. 

Definitely consider visiting both schools. Good luck, and feel free to message if you have any questions! 
</commentText><authorName>bluuuu34343</authorName><authorID>139u8t</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491254945.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfrp8jb</commentID><commentText>This is a fun question because I was making that exact same decision last year. That being said, I  also have lived my whole life in Ithaca so a big reason for choosing Hopkins is that I wanted to experience somewhere else. And FYI, I was deciding between engineering at the two schools. I don't know what program you're interested but I can probably answer about a non engineering program too. I think that you really have to consider what your interests are and what you value. The biggest difference is going to be the location. If you're really really interested in outdoors adventures like skiing, hiking, mountain climbing, or just experiencing endless tracts of beautiful trails and wilderness, Cornell will offer that 10 fold. But, at the cost of being basically in the middle of nowhere with very limited transportation options if you don't have a car. One thing that I have loved about being here, is that not only does Baltimore offer a wide variety of opportunities, including many outdoors stuff, but I can easily go to D.C., NYC, or basically anywhere else on the east coast. I absolutely love Ithaca, but It can get old and one runs out of novel things to do. There are a lot of other things too. Cornell will have many of the benefits of a large school, and Hopkins will have many of the benefits of being on the smaller end (Cornell's expanding enrollment in fact). If you're interested in medicine or public health, Hopkins' proximity to their grad schools makes for some amazing opportunities. If there's anything specific, please ask. </commentText><authorName>IncompetentPotato</authorName><authorID>h5h83</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>62uh5a<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491111024.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfpff3h</commentID><commentText>Nothing is stopping you from trying both and deciding later.</commentText><authorName>GoSh4rks</authorName><authorID>dm0ss</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491122394.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfpmwqs</commentID><commentText>As a double major in both, your GPA will be marginally higher if you do Neuro coz the classes are  less curved based. </commentText><authorName>Anthrax175</authorName><authorID>emibb</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491140113.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfpx0oy</commentID><commentText>Any of those majors are fine pre-med majors. Based on my conversations with friends and my experiences, I don't know if one would be easier than the other. Public Health is the easiest of the three.

Take classes for any or all of them your first year and then decide. You could probably even make it into your second year before you decide; I think the core neuro classes taken during sophomore year count as electives for Mol/Cell Bio. The core math/chemistry/physics requirements will be the same for all three, so you have time. Take Cognitive Neuroscience in the Spring (there's also an intro neuro class in the fall, not required for the major) and see what you think.</commentText><authorName>CrypticParagon</authorName><authorID>8qq4c</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>62o1uu<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491031959.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfo7vnu</commentID><commentText>I was in the MSE department as well as BME. Feel free to PM me with any questions. </commentText><authorName>praeceps93</authorName><authorID>8diwx</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491038452.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfocist</commentID><commentText>EHE here. Our classes are small (10-20 students), but we're a top-10 ranked department in US.</commentText><authorName>ManOverBeard</authorName><authorID>362p3</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491384495.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfudmxs</commentID><commentText>ChemBE is really popular, but everyone in it hates their life.</commentText><authorName>yiqz</authorName><authorID>142uyg</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491251728.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfrn92k</commentID><commentText>I'm an ECE major. PM me! </commentText><authorName>wannabe-hipster</authorName><authorID>hb2w2</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>62ngil<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491051827.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfokxg4</commentID><commentText>I think alumni weekend 2016 swag</commentText><authorName>aznhippos</authorName><authorID>6kykb</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>62jled<comments><comment><commentCreated>1491002753.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfniujl</commentID><commentText>Homewood. They're renovating hella apartments on the top floors of the building and they're super nice now. Also has less mice/roaches than Bradford. Just don't go for a room on the inner corridor on the north side or you'll have the pleasure of hearing every drunk motherfucker's conversation outside of Maxie's at 2am.

No experience with Bradford, but most of my friends and I lived in Homewood during our sophomore year and it was great. You can have a fuckload of people over if you're far enough from the RA room and not have to worry about them being annoying about volume/etc. Only bad thing I have to say about the building is that the laundry room needs more machines, but I've seen the Bradford laundry room and I'd expect you'd have the same problem there. 
</commentText><authorName>StrangeShuckles</authorName><authorID>5jp0x</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>62gf1t<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490936440.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfmevvc</commentID><commentText>Is McCoy what you want? There will probably be openings in all the dorms, although you might have to split into pairs depending on how late your time slot is relative to everyone else</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490951493.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfmqwng</commentID><commentText>I got a 5:40 time slot. Does anyone know the earliest timeslot? How likely will I get commons? I am a double btw.</commentText><authorName>anonymoosea</authorName><authorID>16mz6n</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491211844.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfr2hhv</commentID><commentText>Hi sorry to say but you will most likely get McCoy. Last year all the non-mccoy quads were gone by 6</commentText><authorName>forrnaldehyde</authorName><authorID>xptmx</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491513858.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfwo8cy</commentID><commentText>rip </commentText><authorName>wowfuckthisshit</authorName><authorID>we6b2</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>62ad9e<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490884394.0</commentCreated><commentID>dflfbn8</commentID><commentText>probably so the investigators could smoke up themselves without having to share</commentText><authorName>wowfuckthisshit</authorName><authorID>we6b2</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>6245nx<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490867397.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfl5k5l</commentID><commentText>I once had 6 exams in 6 consecutive time slots. Professors were accommodating and helped me spread them out.</commentText><authorName>CrypticParagon</authorName><authorID>8qq4c</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490815523.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfjylif</commentID><commentText>I've been in that situation before, and have heard talk of being able to do something about it. That being said I went ahead and took the exams anyways, but the feasibility of that may vary depending on your major/year. Your best bet is talking to your professors about it. </commentText><authorName>tercac</authorName><authorID>8utsv</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490856145.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfkwvek</commentID><commentText>If they are final exams that all fall on the same time slot, yes there are policies in place. If not, sorry good luck.</commentText><authorName>BaseLime</authorName><authorID>5r88e</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490861625.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfl114l</commentID><commentText>I would talk to the professors, explain your situation and hope for the best. Low odds of them allowing you to change the day or time of exam so I'd prepare to take them all on the same day if I were you. It sucks but sometimes is unavoidable.</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490790887.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfjp1pl</commentID><commentText>Why would you postpone an exam. They don't overlap. Toughen up and deal with it. You are supposed to be an adult. </commentText><authorName>speedisavirus</authorName><authorID>9t26v</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>623kka<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490872474.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfl9fn8</commentID><commentText>What we need is an app for Stop Texting while walking.  Seriously, get off the fucking phone while walking around St. Paul/Charles Street.  Then all of the kids wonder why drivers are so pissed off at them or nearly run their asses over when they're the ones illegally jaywalking everywhere all of the time while their faces are completely buried in their phones the whole time.  They should spread the Baltimore police state around Baltimore instead of just constantly cracking down on poor minority neighborhoods in the city.  Have 3 cops sit at Charles and St. Paul and 33-36th streets and ticket every single student who jaywalks while on the phone.  They could plug the entire budget deficit of the city in probably 2 weeks there are so many jaywalkers that are trying to kill themselves.  </commentText><authorName>_IDriveADodgeStratus</authorName><authorID>reffm</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>61xfa8<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490838678.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfkgz4k</commentID><commentText>I've heard really bad things about the professor. Not sure about that class in particular, but I think you'd want to be wary of that. His courses are typically not fun and very time consuming.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490728748.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfiavwk</commentID><commentText>Didn't have that when I was there, but for classes where I couldn't get any info from friends I'd just add then drop before the drop period ends. Signed up for 19ish (engineering) credits a semester then dropped anywhere from 1-3 classes depending on the workload and interest level for the classes outside the main required ones. 

You could also not sign up but still go to them if you want and see how it goes. Best to reserve a spot, but even with the classes that fill up the professor usually yellow slips people in.</commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>61wlql<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490696984.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfhwdgd</commentID><commentText>I've heard fairly good things about CTE lab and Biomat classes</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490747538.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfiopif</commentID><commentText>Nanomedicine, Biomaterials, cell/tissue engineering + lab, any of the pharmacology courses</commentText><authorName>JPMasterson</authorName><authorID>s0l5s</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490871683.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfl8vcu</commentID><commentText>I focused in sensors/instrumentation, and the easiest/most straightforward classes were: Circuits (could not believe this counted as an UL), ECE Lab (super, super straightforward and simple material), Robot Sensor/Actuators, and Microfabrication Lab (lazy professors, but really easy/low commitment class). Digital Signal Processing is another good option imo, but I wouldn't say it was *particularly* easy; Prof Weinert is really straightforward though, and you kind of always know what to expect.</commentText><authorName>SecretAgentMemer</authorName><authorID>12ugs9</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>616hhb<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490365955.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfcassc</commentID><commentText>I have a place close to the jhmi stop I'm looking to sublet, PM me.</commentText><authorName>TheLeapIsALie</authorName><authorID>71wzj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490354654.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfc5j79</commentID><commentText>There are shuttles that connect the undergrad campus (charles village), the peabody conservatory (mt. vernon), and med campus. I recommend looking around mt vernon for the following reasons:
1. 10 min. Shuttle ride from med campus (25 min from charles village)
2. Generally safe neighbourhood with better restaurant options than charles village
3. Slightly cheaper rent than charles village
4. More things to do than med campus

If you have access, check out sublet postings in this facebook group.

  https://www.facebook.com/groups/1436274586674571/</commentText><authorName>DottedGlass</authorName><authorID>zryea</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490430654.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfdi0a1</commentID><commentText>I have a room I'd like to sublet, walkable to the med campus (northwest corner of Patterson Park). PM me! Otherwise maybe join the Facebook groups for people who go to the med school or the school of public health (which is right by the med campus) and the FB groups for Butcher's Hill (where I live)/Upper Fells Point, both of which are walkable and will probably have some people in them looking to sublet.    </commentText><authorName>palpablescalpel</authorName><authorID>7cguw</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>60wr4d<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490250501.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfa64a8</commentID><commentText>My 2 cents - really depends on the type of jobs we're talking about. If you're talking about jobs that require much of the specialized technical skills you'd get with an engineering degree, then it's a legitimate concern. But if you could also see yourself in jobs that don't strictly require engineering degrees (e.g., finance, consulting), then BME is perfectly fine; they'd just be looking for analytical and problem solving skills and comfort with quantitative stuff. 

The benefit of BME is that you CAN do premed and still have good degree to fallback on. Because BME overlaps significantly more with premed requirements than other engineering degrees like EE or MechE. But at the same time, engineering degrees in general (including BME), have better job prospects than science majors. For the type of jobs where other engineering majors have an advantage over BME, a BME degree would still have an advantage over science majors like neuro / bio. 

So going back to your concern, it's legitimate for certain career paths. But if you want both premed and engineering, BME is probably the best option. I can't say to what extent being BME makes it to maintain a top GPA for med school; my opinion would be it's much more difficult to maintain a top GPA. But for what it's worth all my BME friends ended up going to very good medical schools or didn't have much trouble finding jobs (to my knowledge). Part of this may be because BME at Hopkins is such a competitive program that it is generally comprised of very driven people with a certain tenacity.</commentText><authorName>hungryhungryhippooo</authorName><authorID>86z7y</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490243795.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfa059w</commentID><commentText>I'm currently a student here. Your concerns are certainly very real. I have had friends that were BME/premed going in, and all of them have dropped one or the other. I'm not saying both can't be done, because I'm sure it certainly has, but you're right, especially at a school like Hopkins where GPA is hard to maintain regardless of your major, having a competitive premed GPA while also majoring BME is difficult. 

I would add that a lot of students come to this school with premed aspirations, but find out that it just isn't for them. This doesn't mean they weren't able to do it, but rather that they found a different path that interested them more. My greatest advice would be to look into the requirements for graduating BME and for getting into med school, then give it a semester or two. If you are on track for both, then great! But if not, then take the time to reevaluate your priorities.

As for your question about the usefulness of a BME degree, I am not in the engineering school so my knowledge may be limited, however I have had 2 of my BME friends describe the BME learning experience as becoming a jack of all trades and master of none. They said to really get involved in BME you'd need to pursue it at the Masters or Doctoral level. One of those two friends recently dropped BME and switched to EE because he felt like he wasn't learning any focused skills. Once again, this is just word of mouth from my 2 friends, so I doubt it translates to all BMEs at this school. Congrats on getting accepted into the program. Although I'm speaking from inexperience, most of my engineering friends that have graduated told me that your job prospects mainly depend on how well you market your skills, how far you network yourself, and what internships you land. 

I hope these answers help. Also I hope I didn't discourage you.</commentText><authorName>kainharvey</authorName><authorID>16eun0</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490305177.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfb067l</commentID><commentText>Ahhhhhhhhhhhhh the 1000000000000 pound elephant in the room.  I will tell you from experience being in the BME program for a long, long time..........BMEs don't know enough for anything.  They don't know enough engineering and their biology knowledge is often shit.  In fact, BMEs are TERRIBLE at biology.  If you put the word 'nano', 'micro', etc. etc. in front of something it sounds 'cool', but in reality the shit often never works because BMEs have very, very poor knowledge of basic science a lot of times.  

For example, I've seen graduate BMEs get frustrated that EDTA wasn't dissolving in water when trying to make buffers.  Hello, if you had basic knowledge of chemistry you'd realize that it needs a pH adjustment AND understand WHY adjusting pH makes it dissolve.  Names will not be named, but I also asked a BME if they used an assay to detect apoptosis after a treatment.....they recommended me to do a MTT assay.....WTF?  Holy shit, this person is getting a PhD from Johns Hopkins in BME?  There are so many BMEs that claim to know biology but have no clue how to do something so basic like a western blot, immuno precipitation, how to flox a gene, how design a primer for PCR and analyze the results on a DNA gel,  etc. etc....

And I've seen BME undergrads forget what DNA does (but they can do stupid linear transformations using matrix algebra!) and I've seen BME undergrads not even know high school basics of acid base chemistry that is so, so ,soooooooooooo essential for molecular biology.  

Most BMEs though are using it as a springboard to get into medical school or for working in the financial industry, which is fine I suppose.  But if you want to do this as a career, I am extremely doubtful.  You don't know enough engineering and definitely, definitely not enough experimental biology.  Nano- something sounds cool until you ask a real biologist who knows that 'EPR effects' for explaining why a tumor is uptaking nanoparticles is basically BS and that all of this nanoshit has so many off target and genotoxic effects that are often ignored.  


If you want to be a hardcore engineer that does some biology--ChemBE is badass.  If you want to do more biology with some tech thrown in--chemical biology is the way to go, they are much, much better at biology and basic science. </commentText><authorName>_IDriveADodgeStratus</authorName><authorID>reffm</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490250958.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfa6i03</commentID><commentText>I'm a current BME/premed going to medical school next year. If you really want both, it can be done, however, if I had the choice to go back in time, I would have chosen one or the other. If you are sure you want medical school to be in your future, than it really doesn't matter what major you choose, and there are many easier, interesting majors than BME. Furthermore, GPA is king for med school, and  most schools do not care how hard you had to work for your GPA. The 3.8 cognitive science major will almost always beat a 3.6 engineering major. Regarding job prospects, I can only comment that the other poster is right with the jack of all trades, master of none concept. I am a computer science minor, and I have more focused, useful skills in compsi than I have in BME. Feel free to PM me any questions if you have them.</commentText><authorName>ar1017</authorName><authorID>79kuu</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490267854.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfajmw3</commentID><commentText>A lot of people here have said useful stuff. If you really, really want med school another major is probably a better option, med (and law as an aside) take GPA **heavily** into account, regardless of major. And sure, you can get a consulting or finance job, but as someone who currently works in consulting I can tell you that your first job out of college will also greatly depend on GPA (though not as much as med school). If you pull off a 3.4 GPA in BME, during interviews at prestigious firms (BCG, McK, Goldman, etc.) you're going to be passed up by the Econ/MechE/Applied Math etc. majors who managed to pull off 3.8+. Your mileage will vary in less prestigious firms. 

Overall, if you can hack it it's very enriching simply for the fact that you get to do design team. If you have other aspirations there are way easier routes to go.</commentText><authorName>firesIncreaseDPS</authorName><authorID>7t1cn</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490313356.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfb72ii</commentID><commentText>In my year there were BMEs who turned out very well (top jobs at Goldman / McKinsey or MIT phds, etc), but that could be a function of the program being highly selective itself and attracting strong students. Also these people had 3.9+ GPAs. If you do well you'll be fine, just make sure you tailor your clubs, experience, and secondary majors / minors to where you want to be.

If you 100% want med school, it's way easier to just do neuro or bio and get a 3.9+ and have some good clubs etc.</commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490269768.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfakwts</commentID><commentText>mofo. you're not even at the school yet. dont worry about not getting a job in four years. speaking as a recent jhu bme graduate ('16)</commentText><authorName>fishmonster69</authorName><authorID>5i47m</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>60k24u<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490121561.0</commentCreated><commentID>df7m8tb</commentID><commentText>So I looked at your link quickly but am kind of unsure what CSA stands for. If you can clarify that'd be helpful. 

As for getting freest produce, i know there is the waverly farmer's market on saturdays. I don't know the exact specifics by the farmers market is a 5-6 blocks away from Homewood campus. Hope this helps!

Edit: just looked a the link and understand what it means by community supported agriculture. I don't know if JHU redditors use the market, but you can likely get more info via Hopkins Facebook  groups. </commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>60jut6<comments><comment><commentCreated>1490085121.0</commentCreated><commentID>df73e4l</commentID><commentText>I know several people who have gotten off the waitlist. Don't lose hope!</commentText><authorName>DottedGlass</authorName><authorID>zryea</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490095527.0</commentCreated><commentID>df7bjxk</commentID><commentText>Make sure you update them on any achievements you've had since you sent in your application! </commentText><authorName>PhosphoErk</authorName><authorID>newap</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490128454.0</commentCreated><commentID>df7p9k9</commentID><commentText>Start drafting a letter to the admissions office right now. You want to demonstrate to them that you're still very interested, highlighting any new developments in your academic life since you submitted your application. 

The worst thing you can possibly do is wait for them to call you. </commentText><authorName>ameriswissy</authorName><authorID>6sqcp</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490117352.0</commentCreated><commentID>df7kwda</commentID><commentText>I got off the waitlist! I also updated them with things I did after applying. It worked out for me and a number of my friends. Good luck!</commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490158451.0</commentCreated><commentID>df8en8s</commentID><commentText>For grad school I got off the waitlist 1 or 2 days after April 15, when everyone else had replied saying they would or wouldn't go. A spot opened up and I jumped on.</commentText><authorName>trashacount12345</authorName><authorID>3w2ki</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490313599.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfb7ajd</commentID><commentText>Hopkins seems pretty open to students who demonstrate interest, especially for the waitlist. Make sure to do that.</commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1494433205.0</commentCreated><commentID>dhd7ywc</commentID><commentText>when do you find out ?
</commentText><authorName>jiglix9</authorName><authorID>11bzdo</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>607ta1<comments /></submission><submission>601uxo<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489864132.0</commentCreated><commentID>df36xff</commentID><commentText>Hello! I graduated last spring with a MechE degree and aerospace concentration, so hopefully I can help out a bit! 

So specifically for the aerospace concentration, that's done solely out of the MechE department. You have to be a MechE to get an aerospace concentration. The program is basically that 5/6 of your technical/MechE electives have to be aerospace-related, most of which are offered within the department itself. We also have a chapter of AIAA on campus, which was rebooted last spring.

I interned at NASA after my junior year, and that was an incredible experience, and I know other people who did internships at Lockheed Martin, SpaceX, and a few other aero-related companies. It is possible, but don't expect Hopkins to be particularly helpful in this regard (but that's true of an internship in any field). As for jobs, I can't help too much in that regard since I'm working on my Masters elsewhere, specifically in AE. 

Hopkins definitely isn't particularly known for aerospace engineering, though I had a really great experience with the concentration. A few of the courses are taught by lecturers who work at APL and a couple other companies in the area, so it's really great in that regard to be taught by people who work in the field every day. At the end of the day, you're getting a mechanical engineering degree from Johns Hopkins, which is already worth a lot, plus some background in AE. If you want to work in aerospace, having a degree from here is certainly going to open more doors than it closes.</commentText><authorName>ameriswissy</authorName><authorID>6sqcp</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489874616.0</commentCreated><commentID>df3b621</commentID><commentText>We recently had a small recruiting event hosted by SpaceX. </commentText><authorName>DottedGlass</authorName><authorID>zryea</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>601mxk<comments /></submission><submission>5zurft<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489915368.0</commentCreated><commentID>df43q6w</commentID><commentText>Orgo 2 is a prereq for Biochem fyi</commentText><authorName>DaNaj420</authorName><authorID>wvsn5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489745419.0</commentCreated><commentID>df19ir2</commentID><commentText>So I took Orgo 1 and Genetics my sophomore fall. It was definitely rough at the time and honestly a bit of an energy drain. In the end, I did do really well in Genetics and did ok in Orgo 1 (I had Tovar). I could have probably studied more for Orgo as I did not take it as seriously and so Orgo 2 was more challenging for me (because I had to partially relearn Orgo 1). 

Depending on the other classes you plan to take, it can be done and I think you can definitely succeed in both. </commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489827112.0</commentCreated><commentID>df2qhp1</commentID><commentText>I was also a neuro major a long, long time ago and biochemistry isn't that bad if you've already taken nervous systems. I have no input on genetics though.</commentText><authorName>nutterbutter9</authorName><authorID>b54q0</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5zenwp<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489566127.0</commentCreated><commentID>dext0f6</commentID><commentText>What are your interests? Are you looking for something that's purely for fun or maybe something more volunteer-oriented? Giving us a little bit to go on will help a lot</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489566537.0</commentCreated><commentID>dextc94</commentID><commentText>HERO was the most rewarding experience of my life. Even if you're not pre-med, the skills you learn as a EMT are not only life-saving, but helps to teach you how to work in emergencies. The classes are time-consuming but are well worth the time-investment. I graduated 2 years ago, and I still miss HERO.</commentText><authorName>palmtreesh526</authorName><authorID>7o37p</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491949054.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg4b4b0</commentID><commentText>On the first Tuesday of the month head into the steam tunnels under AMR I. Wander until you're sure you're lost. Close your eyes, bang on the pipes the times, and wait.

They'll find you.</commentText><authorName>Yawehg</authorName><authorID>6nksr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489552974.0</commentCreated><commentID>dexi2hh</commentID><commentText>Hello u/unproductivelilshit have you ever heard of Camp Kesem? We're a student group that funds and organizes a summer camp for children whose parents have been diagnosed with cancer. We are currently seeking counselors for our camp this year. It's a great opportunity to support an often overlooked demographic. Even if you're not interested in attending the summer camp, there are plenty of ways to get involved. We have positions available in operations, development, volunteer, and outreach. If you're interested in attending the camp, you can apply [here](https://campscui.active.com/orgs/CampKesem#/selectSessions/1664902). If you're interested in getting involved in other ways, you can contact jhu.volunteer@campkesem.org. If you have questions feel free to ask!</commentText><authorName>CampKesemJHU</authorName><authorID>164zt4</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489553843.0</commentCreated><commentID>dexiuqg</commentID><commentText>I'd suggest the English Club if you have even a tiny bit of interest in the humanities and/or "appearing more well-rounded." It's super chill, open to everyone, &amp; has some pretty cool events (stuff where you can touch really rare books, talk to grad students &amp; professors, free food, etc.) It's also great for networking if you're a humanities major of any kind.

You can literally come to like 2 events/meetings a year &amp; still be considered a member. Plus it's small so it's easy to get super involved if you want. There's a pretty dead fb page for it but I don't have the link atm. PM me if you're interested in getting on the mailing list tho.</commentText><authorName>neerpoom</authorName><authorID>14rsm1</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489568560.0</commentCreated><commentID>dexuzh5</commentID><commentText>As the other guy said, give us a list of your interests and we can tell you about clubs that may be open and connect you with members of those groups. I have a couple that come to mind in terms of being pretty open to join, but i kind of need your interest areas to give you proper suggestions. </commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489570976.0</commentCreated><commentID>dexx02h</commentID><commentText>I played rugby (c/o '02) and still keep in touch with my teammates and other alumni from the team. It was a very welcoming environment, even for the few teetotallers on the team - they were the most reliable drivers on our out of town trips.</commentText><authorName>mogner</authorName><authorID>9n0ft</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489639599.0</commentCreated><commentID>dez56xg</commentID><commentText>There's a club that volunteers at an animal shelter nearby</commentText><authorName>themodernbelle</authorName><authorID>120x32</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489661372.0</commentCreated><commentID>deznck2</commentID><commentText>Definitely recommend tutorial project! Even though you can't join right now for this spring, you can join next fall! You get paired up with an elementary student and work with them throughout the entire semester - it's super fulfilling. Look out for the info sessions/meet &amp; greet next fall :) </commentText><authorName>sincerelypicasso</authorName><authorID>z7bws</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489986704.0</commentCreated><commentID>df57g6f</commentID><commentText> Check out Musicare. They organize small performances at retirement homes and hospitals. You just need to sign up before the next trip. I think the deadline is this Friday.

Either email them jhu.musicare@gmail.com
Or look at their fb page https://www.facebook.com/Musicare-233751197026786/?fref=ts</commentText><authorName>DottedGlass</authorName><authorID>zryea</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5zdao3<comments /></submission><submission>5z7eev<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489467972.0</commentCreated><commentID>devxbww</commentID><commentText>He usually answers emails, but he is pretty busy. Is he your direct advisor? You could probably email your faculty advisor first and have them email him? Or you could call him&#8212;his phone number is definitely on his page.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1491949107.0</commentCreated><commentID>dg4b5tt</commentID><commentText>He was my advisor. I always had to physically go to his office and wait, but he never failed to help me.</commentText><authorName>Yawehg</authorName><authorID>6nksr</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5z79nq<comments /></submission><submission>5z1hnu<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489398728.0</commentCreated><commentID>deuqsy7</commentID><commentText>I'm finishing my BME MSE in a few months and I think I can answer, however its best if you talk to someone who started last year (I started 2 years ago).  Basically the program changed a lot between my year and the year after me.

When I joined you were required to do a thesis, everyone was funded and paid for, and the program took 2 years.  However, the fund that paid the Masters students ran out after my year so there is no more funding available.

The lack of funding for Masters is really standard across the US though.  Its very rare to be funded unless you go for a PhD.  If you want to talk about paying for it you are best asking a student in the year after me since I didn't pay for it myself.  But I think they did it like every other masters student: just get a student loan from a bank somewhere.

As for the classes, in my year we didn't take any classes to bring us up to speed.  My background was in mechanical engineering so I need a lot of help with biology stuff, but there were other masters students with backgrounds in biology who helped me.  And in turn I helped them with things like MATLAB and computer stuff.

So yeah, there is no prerequisite courses required if you are Masters student and you don't have time to take undergrad courses anyway.  Only courses above a certain level count towards the Masters degree requirement and there is a lot of courses to take in a year so you will be booked.

So yeah you will need to find friends to help with courses and you will need to find a loan to pay.  Although potentially there is some scholarships I'm not aware of (talk to someone the year ahead of you).

But in the end this is kind of the situation everywhere.  If you manage to find another Masters program that will pay you while you attend, you may want to seriously consider it, but Hopkins is a great school so I imagine it will still be worth it.

Hope that helps</commentText><authorName>FreeRunningEngineer</authorName><authorID>eh5fq</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489402974.0</commentCreated><commentID>deutn5l</commentID><commentText>I'm studying ECE as a master's student this year and I did BME undergrad at Hopkins, so I know a handful of students who entered the BME MSE program this past fall; I'll do my best to answer, but I honestly don't know much about the funding situation.

As far as I know, most students don't need to take any extra classes that are typical 'prerequisites' when they start. You're required to take two "Systems Bioengineering" (SBE) Courses (there are three available) regardless of the degree type that you go for. I took all three as an undergrad and I would say there aren't any prerequisites per se, but they all required use of MATLAB at some point, and I believe it's assumed that you have taken the basic math courses (Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, and Multivariable Calculus). I'm not sure if you've taken those, but I wouldn't be *too* worried if you hadn't. You'll have friends and you could catch up on the specific tools on your own time. SBE I and II are more related, and SBE III is its own thing entirely.

The rest of your courses just need to be 400 level or above (i.e. 'graduate' level classes) and you'll likely have quite a lot of flexibility there. Even if you don't have a prerequisite for a certain class, if you're a graduate student especially, most professors will let you in regardless (not that that is a guarantee and I'm sure there are some students who don't have that experience, but I've never had any problems just emailing professors, explaining that I don't have the prereq, and being allowed in anyway). That said, it does depend a bit on the specific class, your background, and how much time you'll have to dedicate to it (if you are missing prereqs). Like if you try to jump into a 600 level CS class without any programming experience (for a computational biology concentration)...that'll likely be a struggle.

Personally, I think the master's is very doable in 3 semesters (I and a couple friends are completing ours in 2 semesters), which means that may be a little less money (not much...but still). I'm not sure about BME MSE, but you can maybe ask about how part-time would work if you want to try to finish in two semesters, but you may have one or two courses left (so you basically pay per credit in the final semester, which could save you quite a bit of money). I know it's possible for ECE because I know someone doing that, but again, you'll want to ask the BME department.

There is a chance, if you get really involved in a lab and a project, that you could get some funding from the lab or a project grant, but that's a very big maybe (I have been paid a bit from a grant, but that's small fry compared to tuition), so I wanted to throw that out there, but I definitely wouldn't count on it. Honestly, I'm not sure what else to say for staying afloat and not drowning in debt for grad school...the majority of people I know either are in debt, have their parents pay for it, or they worked for a couple years and saved up before going to grad school.

Sorry that was so long, but I hope it helped a bit.  Feel free to PM me if you have any questions!</commentText><authorName>SecretAgentMemer</authorName><authorID>12ugs9</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489452484.0</commentCreated><commentID>devj7nk</commentID><commentText>I also got in for grad school, so I can't comment specifically on your questions. However, funding for higher ed is a huge deal. I probably wouldn't go if it wasn't fully funded. This is a common question at /r/GradSchool, some people there will definitely be able to speak more to this.</commentText><authorName>kinnunenenenen</authorName><authorID>bg18v</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489461680.0</commentCreated><commentID>devrj50</commentID><commentText>Hi otolithic - I have applied for MSE BME also and haven't heard back from JHU. When did you hear back? And, did you receive a letter in the mail or an email about your acceptance? Thanks!</commentText><authorName>nprakash214</authorName><authorID>165s6l</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5z1faa<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489399750.0</commentCreated><commentID>deurhyz</commentID><commentText>I personally vote for finding a friend who's staying over the summer who is willing to let you store it in a corner; completely free and you can get it pretty easily once you come back</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489431858.0</commentCreated><commentID>dev5tsh</commentID><commentText>I know some friends got together and rented a storage locker from a place nearby. I don't know the name, but on google maps, you can probably find it under "storage locker" search. Reason I said multiple people rented one is that it's cheaper to split the costs since you probably don't have enough stuff to fill up an entire locker. But maybe you do, I don't know. 

Obviously storing with a friend is the cheapest option, but may be difficult as people go back home and stuff. Good luck!</commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489463778.0</commentCreated><commentID>devtfp6</commentID><commentText>There are storage companies but they are very expensive. Expect to spend at least $250 per month.  Find a friend to store your stuff or post a request on the free and for sale fb group</commentText><authorName>DottedGlass</authorName><authorID>zryea</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489468130.0</commentCreated><commentID>devxh3d</commentID><commentText>I used the Hopkins Movers. They're pretty great&#8212;always show up on time, pack everything away pretty efficiently, and move all of it back pretty quickly, too. They lost one of my boxes for a few days, which was pretty irritating, but I'm pretty sure that doesn't happen very often and they got it back to me pretty quickly.

A lot of people also split storage with friends, and I don't think it's that expensive because I was planning to use a storage space that was like $30/month and split it with a friend. The reason I ended up using HM is because they were much more convenient.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5ywujh<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489344089.0</commentCreated><commentID>detsizz</commentID><commentText>Woah, please do not waste your stipend on one of those new luxury buildings! Those are for wealthy undergrads, not grad students. You're in grad school now, so just accept that "luxury" is not going to describe your living situation for the next several years. If you want to actually save money, get a room in a house with other grad students/young professionals for $500-800 in CV, Remington, or hampden. You can live a bit more luxuriously in a fixed up rowhome with roommates and get more bang for your buck. If you want to avoid undergrads, go for Hampden--lots of grad students live there. Live alone: try one of the apts on west university or an apt in a split up rowhome in CV, Hampden, Remington; you can get an a studio-1 bedroom for $900-1400, but may have to sacrifice some amenities on the lower end. Realistically, on a grad student stipend you will probably be using one entire paycheck for rent/utilities if you live alone. </commentText><authorName>bmorebio</authorName><authorID>la3ol</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489404812.0</commentCreated><commentID>deuutrb</commentID><commentText>So I've lived in the area for ~5 years now and have moved every single year so I can give a bit of insight into the apartments that I liked/disliked (and what I've heard from friends who have also been here 4-5 years).

I would recommend against going with a place like Nine East 33rd or the Varsity, which are really just dorm rooms 2.0. I lived in the Varsity as an undergrad and that was a complete waste of money (tiny rooms, meh amenities, small kitchens, weird furniture, super overpriced, etc), and I've heard/seen that Nine East 33rd isn't that much better (though I admit I am very jealous of the location). 

I lived in the Guilford (note that it is different from Guilford Manor, which is just a block away) for a year and it was pretty nice, though it was a decently long way to walk. Pretty spacious rooms, usually large kitchens, etc. The downsides were that the AC units would only be able to be either hot or cold (the apartment building as a whole would switch at around the season change), and there's generally no laundry unit in the apartment (I might just be spoiled by the fact that I had one in the room for so long).

Hopkins House - I know quite a few people who have lived there, including professors and grad students. Honestly...I would avoid it, based on what I've heard. It's also, imo, quite far from campus in terms of walking (~25+ minutes walking, which would lead to...like more than an hour of walking around every day if you go back and forth more than once).

UniOne - Have a handful of friends who live here, and they generally like it!  I've been to a couple apartments there, and they seem pretty spacious and nice, but the downside is that I think it really depends on who actually owns the apartment. I think it's really walkable too.

Marylander - Another place I've been to tons and had friends who lived there last year. Okay apartment space, but they mostly hated the apartment because of the management and annoying things...like apparently they'll sometimes just tell you they're turning off water access for the majority of the day so you can't shower or use the toilet or anything? Maybe someone else who actually lived there can confirm, but I would personally avoid.

I've never lived in a rowhome, but I have friends who spent a few years there and it's apparently very affordable and spacious, but could be more of a hassle (I think the appeal of a lot of apartments are that they kind of 'take care' of everything for you). In terms of location, I personally love Hampden, but I think it's a bit of a longer walk to campus (not too bad though). There's also the Ambassador Apartments, which I've heard is nice. I actually found my apartment this year through zillow, and it's a super nice place, so that might be worth looking into.</commentText><authorName>SecretAgentMemer</authorName><authorID>12ugs9</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489468667.0</commentCreated><commentID>devxyhc</commentID><commentText>If you're set on something luxurious, you Nine East is okay in terms of everything looking real nice, it's in a really great location, etc. But it is super small and super expensive. I've also heard a lot of complaints about the security making it really difficult to bring guests (being super rude, etc.) and also having difficulties with management.

I think the best bet for you would be [Remington Row](http://www.theremingtonrow.com/), which is *really* nice and also cheap (~$1200 for a 2BR/month, IIRC)&#8212;but this is because it's in a bad location. It's brand new and looks absolutely amazing, and is right next to R House, which is also a new food-court place that's pricey but good. That's about a 5 minute walk from the southernmost part of campus.

There's also The Academy (previously the Varsity), which is a little cheaper than 9E and in my opinion, a little nicer&#8212;but still quite small. It's definitely really nice though, and there are in-unit washer/dryers and it's furnished, which I appreciate a lot just for the convenience.

You can also take a look at Village Lofts, though if you're looking for a 2BR those go officially for over $3400/month&#8212;but if you find someone and get it through someone else's lease, can be as low as $1500/month, which is a *really* good deal for how nice those apartments are. Finding one of those is really tricky though.

In general, for cheaper things, you can look at the Charles or the Blackstone, which are basically write across the street from campus, the Guilford, the Marylander, the Carlton, the Carlyle, Uni One, or Uni West. I don't know too much about those ones, but I have some friends who have lived there/are planning on living there, so you could look into those as well.

I highly recommend looking into Remington Row for what you're looking for&#8212;it looks really nice, and I would have looked more into it but my parents are not happy with the area it's in.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489535323.0</commentCreated><commentID>dex26tk</commentID><commentText>Telephone building might be more to your liking. It is on the pricier side but it's very nice and it's more "grown up" luxury than places like nine east that's more like a beefed up dorm than anything. 

And it's only a 5 min walk from campus. So like equidistant from the Marylander to campus 

Edit: also comes with washer/dryer in the apartment. I lived there my senior year and hands down my fav place I've ever lived ever. Those high ass ceilings are to die for. Also, you get roof access if you ignore a sign or two ;)</commentText><authorName>WombatlikeWoah</authorName><authorID>7oloj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489320287.0</commentCreated><commentID>detiv1v</commentID><commentText>Also! Can you tell me how bad it is taking the shuttle to wal-mart for groceries? Does it take a long time to get there? I was planning on shopping at Eddie's Market but I've heard it's overpriced...</commentText><authorName>a2z95</authorName><authorID>mdd34</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489364440.0</commentCreated><commentID>deu1mpk</commentID><commentText>I have no real advice to give, save that I lived in Hopkins House for the better part of a decade and that the new management has really let the place go.  My thirteenth floor apartment flooded three times in as many years.</commentText><authorName>nwf</authorName><authorID>45vec</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490101912.0</commentCreated><commentID>df7fa9j</commentID><commentText>Don't waste money on nine East 33rd....The rent works out to something bat shit insane, like a $900k-$1 million dollar 30 year mortgage for some of those units.

As a matter of fact, skip all massive apartment complexes and move into a row home that has a place for rent.  The huge apartment units usually have shite for facilities management, often have pest problems (mice, fleas, roaches, bedbugs) because there are lots of people living&#8203; in one spot, and they tend to be more expensive.   I've used university haven management to rent my place around CV and Remington now for going on 6 years. They own row homes and have units for rent.  Fantastic landlords who have literally responded in less than 1 hour when I needed something fixed.  I rent in CV and walk everywhere, even all the way to Hampden.  If you need a car, rent a zip car for the day.</commentText><authorName>_BaltimoreBastard_</authorName><authorID>13rh4s</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490752148.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfit67u</commentID><commentText>Personally, I would move a little further from campus and bike/take circulator/shuttle to campus.  Remington and Hampden would be great for graduate students, and I knew quite a few that lived in these neighborhoods when I was a student.  The scene is a little bit more grown up. More bars, restaurants, music venues, farmers markets, breweries, etc.  You can easily get a room for about $500-700 a month in a shared housing.  Hell, my mortgage payment in Hampden is probably significantly less than most 2 bedroom apartments surrounding campus.  If you could get a place cheap enough I would use the remaining money for a car because Baltimore does not have great public transportation.</commentText><authorName>kittycatcate</authorName><authorID>4z9ql</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489374387.0</commentCreated><commentID>deu8wff</commentID><commentText>I really enjoyed the Guilford as an undergrad. It's just a bit further than most places but was one of the nicest. </commentText><authorName>mlbvsnba</authorName><authorID>6z3eu</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489479234.0</commentCreated><commentID>dew6nym</commentID><commentText>So...do you guys really think Nine East 33rd would be that bad? I think I can put up with undergrads in exchange for a washing machine and central A/C...and I know I can afford it and have plenty of spending money left over. </commentText><authorName>a2z95</authorName><authorID>mdd34</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5ypv13<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489240603.0</commentCreated><commentID>desbowl</commentID><commentText>Probably not. I remember I couldn't take a class S/U if I wanted it to count towards my humanities credits. But I think it's by department, can't hurt to ask your advisor.</commentText><authorName>DatBlizzard</authorName><authorID>9ktyk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489242150.0</commentCreated><commentID>descdy6</commentID><commentText>From [the academic catalog](http://e-catalog.jhu.edu/undergrad-students/academic-policies/requirements-for-a-bachelors-degree/#distributiontext)

&gt; In Arts and Sciences, courses taken for the distribution requirement may be taken for a letter grade or for Satisfactory/Unsatisfactory credit. Courses passed with a letter grade of D or better, or passed with a Satisfactory grade, will fulfill the distribution requirement

&gt; In Engineering, each department determines whether or not the Satisfactory/Unsatisfactory grading option will be permitted for courses used to satisfy the distribution requirement.</commentText><authorName>pyroclasts</authorName><authorID>g06lu</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5ynr08<comments><comment><commentCreated>1489217640.0</commentCreated><commentID>derx25y</commentID><commentText>English if you're a TA </commentText><authorName>wowfuckthisshit</authorName><authorID>we6b2</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489202765.0</commentCreated><commentID>derklkn</commentID><commentText>Chinese for sure so you can understand your professors, especially if you wanna be premed.</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489393309.0</commentCreated><commentID>deun159</commentID><commentText>Honestly unless you have prior experience learning a language and want to study it at at least the intermediate level, I'd avoid taking a language. There's nothing wrong with starting a new language, but you won't be able to take the interesting upper level classes that involve deep reading and writing and will be "wasting" your time on elementary classes that you can take on your own either online or elsewhere. </commentText><authorName>gogogadgt</authorName><authorID>dk5tr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489218992.0</commentCreated><commentID>dery15x</commentID><commentText>I enjoyed Hindi a lot, though I only took the beginners classes.  It's a small fun class, and the professor was a very sweet older lady.  She also hosted Indian dinners at the Interfaith Center about once per month.</commentText><authorName>water_in_the_forest</authorName><authorID>e8rkg</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489219137.0</commentCreated><commentID>dery50j</commentID><commentText>In a serious reply, I know Spanish is fairly popular. But that might be biased because my friends are the ones taking Spanish. Personally, I'm not doing a language but I know there is a good amount of room for exploring new ones. </commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489577823.0</commentCreated><commentID>dey26po</commentID><commentText>If you're interested in both German and Japanese, you can always register for both classes and pick which one you like better during the add/drop period.  

I think all of the intro language classes are structured similarly so I'd pick whichever you'd find most fun.  If you're still stuck you can consider whether you would like to study abroad and if so, where, and pick that language.  </commentText><authorName>hopelepoh</authorName><authorID>9vxtm</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490672032.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfhbygk</commentID><commentText>German is a good program here if you're willing to put in the work!</commentText><authorName>Arsdivine</authorName><authorID>y1hw4</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5x2vap<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488497129.0</commentCreated><commentID>deeyqjh</commentID><commentText>Yeah definitely too easy. Elements is for total beginners. I had 4 years of French before college and I took Intermediate 1 and 2 and found those to be really easy as well. With 5 yrs experience, I think Advanced would be perfectly fine. I found Advanced to be slightly harder than the IB French I took in HS.</commentText><authorName>drjsc</authorName><authorID>b190k</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5wyv8c<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488462199.0</commentCreated><commentID>deeimx4</commentID><commentText>I *believe* you have trouble getting a street parking pass anyway if your apartment building provides parking. 

As far as I know there are no garages by there (closest is like the hospital?), so you really just need to scout out some roads around there with no permit requirements </commentText><authorName>nah_you_good</authorName><authorID>4pd7d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489265835.0</commentCreated><commentID>desjzf1</commentID><commentText>How often will you be using your car? Parking on Charles St at the right time of day or on W. Bishops St is free (as is Canterbury and the houses close to the little roundabout down Canterbury), and at least on the latter you wouldn't have to move during the day. There aren't any lots around here though afaik. Any lots are commercially owned (e.g. MOM's in Hampden).</commentText><authorName>amnnn</authorName><authorID>bwl9i</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5wxkz1<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488426832.0</commentCreated><commentID>dedqpvu</commentID><commentText>It's traditionally been April 1st.

However, something to learn about Hopkins - it's composed of many little bureaucracies that don't always communicate to each other or with us, so webpages often conflict. I imagine the portal is more recently updated but the pessimist in me would caution against trusting either.</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488459449.0</commentCreated><commentID>deeh11o</commentID><commentText>I know for a fact it was mid-March last year if that gives you any hope!</commentText><authorName>strukbylightnin</authorName><authorID>k844d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488440413.0</commentCreated><commentID>dee2vjl</commentID><commentText>If its anything like grad admissions, the dates are made up and the points don't matter.

I was supposed to hear by the 1st for my grad program, didn't hear from them the 1st, 2nd, 3rd, etc.

Finally on the 10th I was accepted into my #2, and then Hopkins emails me on the 11th saying "welcome aboard." Glad I was sluggish putting in the deposit for that #2...</commentText><authorName>BadEThrowaway</authorName><authorID>wbula</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5wsu18<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488402228.0</commentCreated><commentID>ded5sju</commentID><commentText>Sculpture garden gazebo hands down</commentText><authorName>amattadohb</authorName><authorID>5u9gs</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488411528.0</commentCreated><commentID>dedccvz</commentID><commentText>UTL gazebo 

Fire pit in the woods behind the rec center, not on-campus but very close by 

McCoy radio station space - i'm in student radio so I chill here a lot



</commentText><authorName>StrangeShuckles</authorName><authorID>5jp0x</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488427158.0</commentCreated><commentID>dedr1j4</commentID><commentText>Interfaith Center</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489577204.0</commentCreated><commentID>dey1rcm</commentID><commentText>Remsen 101</commentText><authorName>krushkingdom</authorName><authorID>nb8bd</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5wk83j<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488268490.0</commentCreated><commentID>dearhfz</commentID><commentText>I can speak as a former premed neuro freshman!

You will probably take an introductory neuro class (Intro to Neuro or BBC, basically the same class with different styles) followed by Cog Neuro (unless they changed this requirement). You might end up taking intro chem/bio depending on your AP's; these classes are ok. I'd probably take Calculus if you need it still. Mostly, freshman year has a pretty wide latitude for you to take intro sociology or creative writing (IFP here) or really whatever sounds interesting (e.g. First Year Japanese).</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488694063.0</commentCreated><commentID>deiiaql</commentID><commentText>I took the engineering versions of the physics classes. Having taken AP Physics C, Physics I was trivial. Physics II, on the other hand, covered a lot of material that we didn't cover in Physics C, so it was more difficult. However, having taken Physics C definitely made physics II easier since it gave me a lot of the foundational knowledge that the class built on.

If you have Physics C credit, I would use it. You won't really gain anything by taking the intro physics classes here.</commentText><authorName>tomjerry777</authorName><authorID>none</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488947297.0</commentCreated><commentID>demsey3</commentID><commentText>Through the fire and storm, we march on.  Facing never-ceasing gales, we put our heads down and press on into the storm.  Crevices suddenly appear and swallow many of our comrades -dropped and gone.  There is almost no hope.  But we are soldiers, we will march on until our final days.</commentText><authorName>SassyJazzBreaker</authorName><authorID>yzwqf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488326484.0</commentCreated><commentID>debos7k</commentID><commentText>If you're talking about Physics for biological sciences, I have heard that the class as a whole is slightly easier than the one for physical sciences, but the curve is a lot more generous for the latter. I'm going to assume you're asking about the physical sciences class.

As someone who took Physics C mech in HS and Physics 1 here, I'd say that the difficulty is around the same, but exams can get tricky. Averages are always in the high 60's low 70's range, but, again, the grading scale compensates for the difficulty. As for Physics 2, I'm currently taking it right now, and I find it substantially harder than Physics 1 since it is very calculus intensive/conceptually demanding.</commentText><authorName>CraftyRice</authorName><authorID>uh6oe</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5wb5b7<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488443295.0</commentCreated><commentID>dee53h2</commentID><commentText>You cannot get into computer ethics as a freshman&#8212;there are too few seats even for some juniors to get in. Also, unless it's taught by Kosaraju, all the professors who have been teaching it recently have been assigning a huge amount of writing and reading assignments. Other than that, this schedule is definitely manageable :) Have fun!

As for advice, the midterms in Discrete usually catch people off guard. Study the proof templates in the book, Castello loves them and they will really help on tests.</commentText><authorName>parkourdeer</authorName><authorID>qo1k5</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488162971.0</commentCreated><commentID>de8s01f</commentID><commentText>you don't need to take the lab for Java, doesn't really help with anything. otherwise looks fine. </commentText><authorName>StrangeShuckles</authorName><authorID>5jp0x</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488167832.0</commentCreated><commentID>de8voit</commentID><commentText>I'm a Freshman CS/math major and my fall semester was very similar to yours (only I took an additional H/S class and I took the honors version of calc 3 - 18 credits total).  It was definitely doable but it was a lot of work at times.  Expository writing is easy and so is Java, especially if you've had prior programming experience.  Discrete math isn't terribly difficult in terms of material but the tests are long and the prof who teaches it barely curves.  Also you have to learn how to write proofs which may be hard depending on who you are.  Haven't taken Computer Ethics yet but one credit classes are usually really easy.  Honors calc 3 was fun but hard, but I heard that regular calc 3 (I'm assuming you're not doing honors) is pretty easy.  So all in all, your only real "hard" class will be discrete, everything else should be easy.  You schedule is definitely doable, and might even be a bit on the easy side, especially if you say you're mathematically inclined.  You'll certainly have harder semesters than this. </commentText><authorName>Kim-Jong-Deux</authorName><authorID>mq4pw</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488177081.0</commentCreated><commentID>de92sw5</commentID><commentText>Dude, you've probably been asking questions every other day. Sure, maybe you're just trying to be smart about your decisions. But come on man, if you want to be successful in life you really need to learn to be able to make them yourself.</commentText><authorName>MyTribeCalledQuest</authorName><authorID>4omi4</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5wamy3<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488169376.0</commentCreated><commentID>de8wtui</commentID><commentText>All campus dorms have Ethernet in each room, which is a gigabit connection. 

Wireless is pretty good. I just ran a speed test and it's 25 Mbps up and 20 Mbps down at the moment, but Usually I see it closer to 75 up and down. Ping is good at less than 10 ms. 

Also, all dorms have wifi and Ethernet. Also, all of Homewood campus outside is covered with wifi so you can do your work outdoors as well. 

Honestly, the Internet is good here that I hate being at home because of having to wait and deal with poor internet connection. </commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488171557.0</commentCreated><commentID>de8ygza</commentID><commentText>It's pretty good</commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5w2dv1<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488040219.0</commentCreated><commentID>de6y2gb</commentID><commentText>Since Mac is basically Unix, it's probably the easiest from the get go. If I had something that started out as Windows, I'd probably just install Ubuntu on it and do all my programming on that.

All you really need in the end is something that can run vim or emacs.</commentText><authorName>MyTribeCalledQuest</authorName><authorID>4omi4</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488029500.0</commentCreated><commentID>de6tojt</commentID><commentText>It doesn't matter. Does your computer have an internet browser?  Then your computer is good enough for CS.   Pick whatever you like/are comfortable with. </commentText><authorName>aWickedGangAreWe</authorName><authorID>6jzfr</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488083827.0</commentCreated><commentID>de7khdf</commentID><commentText>Windows. Windows will run Windows software and windows 10 has basically built in Ubuntu bash shell. Plus if you need a real Linux environment you can install X distribution free in a VM or dual boot. You cannot do that on a Mac for free if you need Windows. I've taken courses that the defacto environment was windows and visual studio is the choice unless you really hate your life in that environment.</commentText><authorName>speedisavirus</authorName><authorID>9t26v</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488084072.0</commentCreated><commentID>de7kns6</commentID><commentText>&gt; Hey guys, I'm back.

I lol-ed


I'd vote windows if you're comfortable with it. A lot of the random softwares you might use tend to work better on windows than mac in my experience. 

For phones, it doesn't really matter. I know some people with flip phones, some with android, some with iphone. Campus itself is pretty safe so you shouldn't have to be afraid of losing your phone imo</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vyrwm<comments><comment><commentCreated>1488008097.0</commentCreated><commentID>de6fvyz</commentID><commentText>The aquarium and science center are fairly fun to do, the various navy boat tours are also pretty cool if it's not too hot outside.

Completely unrelated, I think we all know your username now, so you can probably drop the "I'll be joining Hopkins this fall" bit and just jump straight into your question lol</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487998562.0</commentCreated><commentID>de685be</commentID><commentText>National Aquarium and crab dinner afterwards</commentText><authorName>18418871</authorName><authorID>kqbiv</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488001490.0</commentCreated><commentID>de6ao67</commentID><commentText>Ice skating at Pandora rink in inner harbor </commentText><authorName>wowfuckthisshit</authorName><authorID>we6b2</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1490324423.0</commentCreated><commentID>dfbgql6</commentID><commentText>I was a grad student there for two years and lived near the Inner Harbor (straddling the line of mediocre and ghetto). So experience as an undergrad living closer to Homewood may be different.

But anyway, it was nice to have it. My then-girlfriend-now-wife liked to go running in the mornings there since it was more interesting. And we both used to like to hit up some of the happy hours at the otherwise over-priced and over-hyped restaurants.

It is a tourist destination mostly so expect some chains (why people go to chain restaurants when traveling, I will never understand) but also just assume that most places are not geared towards the locals. 

However, around the harbor was nice too! You have PowerPlant live, Harbor East (even more $$$), Fells Points (not too far) and Federal Hill. Those places are fun...assuming you don't need to park.

I will say, one of my favorite days was actually towards the end of my time in Baltimore. We were moving soon and were supposed to be working, or at the very least packing, but we both played hookie. We went to Miss Shirley's which was always packed whenever we could otherwise go, and then we played tourist. We took the water taxi all around, we hit up Max's in Fells Point, we walked the harbor, etc. That was a good day!

</commentText><authorName>jwink3101</authorName><authorID>6asud</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vypoy<comments><comment><commentCreated>1487991502.0</commentCreated><commentID>de61wv0</commentID><commentText>**PEABODY AT A GLANCE**

Hours for Library and Exhibit Gallery:

Sunday and Monday: Closed

Tuesday -Thursday: 10am-5pm

Friday - Saturday: 10am-3pm

 

Visitors are permitted to take photographs.  The library is a closed-stacks facility, so visitors are not allowed upstairs.
[
Source](http://guides.library.jhu.edu/c.php?g=202582&amp;p=1336208)</commentText><authorName>jrjohnstone</authorName><authorID>92656</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487988517.0</commentCreated><commentID>de5z9b4</commentID><commentText>Homewood students are able to visit the Peabody Library. I haven't tried going into the rest of the Peabody campus, but you should be able to visit it too.</commentText><authorName>tomjerry777</authorName><authorID>none</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1489271974.0</commentCreated><commentID>desmqmz</commentID><commentText>Yup! You will</commentText><authorName>andreaslordos</authorName><authorID>tm22o</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vss06<comments><comment><commentCreated>1487910271.0</commentCreated><commentID>de4k2ih</commentID><commentText>Forgot to add -- the place is on Elkader Road, in Ednor Gardens, 6 minutes from JHU driving, or 8 minutes on a bike.</commentText><authorName>nathanclingan</authorName><authorID>mdblk</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vrfg3<comments><comment><commentCreated>1487898989.0</commentCreated><commentID>de493b2</commentID><commentText>Betas are a little boring and lame to keep as pets. Better to get a pike and watch him get aggressive towards his own reflection, or get a Fiji and appreciate his brilliant white color.</commentText><authorName>my_gamertag_wastaken</authorName><authorID>pb85b</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487904356.0</commentCreated><commentID>de4e94z</commentID><commentText>In the two years I lived on campus, I think RAs or other campus employees were in my room maybe three times total. I had some goldfish my freshman year, and I was able to put them in a spot that couldn't be seen through an open door. They were never found by anyone who I didn't want to see them. 

I don't know anyone who got caught with pets. I guess they'd be confiscated, but that's a very low risk. You should have a warning before someone comes into your room, which gives you time to hide the betta if necessary. </commentText><authorName>Jernon</authorName><authorID>48r1w</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488079980.0</commentCreated><commentID>de7hqti</commentID><commentText>I have no idea what would happen, but it should be pretty easy to not be caught. There are room checks by the RAs in the middle and at the end of each semester (at least for me in AMR I), but you are told about them several days in advance.</commentText><authorName>strukbylightnin</authorName><authorID>k844d</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vo4sk<comments><comment><commentCreated>1487854967.0</commentCreated><commentID>de3la25</commentID><commentText>Between the dates you listed, in pretty sure the university is completely closed. That means all students must be out of campus housing. Some international students go back home until the spring semester starts. But if you are doing intersession, it might not be worth going back to India for a week. In which case I recommend living with family/friends for a week. You can also move back in once campus opens after New Years and just stay in the dorms. 

There are no Hopkins specific activities during Christmas as the university is closed. But there are events to do on campus. Res Life also hosts events during the intersession break. 

Hope this helps!

Also, side note: Baltimore winter is not harsh. At worst, it just really windy, which makes it seem really cold. But the last 2 weeks have been around 60 deg F, and warm enough to enjoy without a jacket (or a thin sweater). But you should still have a heavy jacket for winds/snow (which we didn't have this year). </commentText><authorName>you_are_who</authorName><authorID>csboj</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1488080264.0</commentCreated><commentID>de7hy5u</commentID><commentText>Campus housing does totally close so you definitely have to stay somewhere else. Staying for all of intersession as a freshman is a little uncommon as those who take a class during that time typically take B'More (a freshman only class that is only the last week of intersession). If you were going to do B'More or not take anything during intersession, then you can extend break by a couple of weeks, which would probably make going home worth it.
Winter really isn't too bad! Trust me, you can make it!</commentText><authorName>strukbylightnin</authorName><authorID>k844d</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vnonp<comments><comment><commentCreated>1487854253.0</commentCreated><commentID>de3ktg1</commentID><commentText>There are some good places to live within walking distance. I'm not sure what your price range is, but living in charles village within a few blocks of the university or Hampden is safe. With a car that makes things a little easier and broaden's your options. Baltimore doesn't have as much stuff going on as some bigger cities, but there is some great food, cultural events, and JHU events, not to mention the fact that DC is an $8, 40min train ride away. There are movie theaters in the inner harbor, which is accessible through the Charm City Circulator (free and easy to use). 
I like that there is a lot going on at Hopkins, and that there's that university feel of stuff going on. Baltimore has its ups and its downs, but I feel like people tend to focus on the downs more. Find friends that like to get out there and do things in the city, and your experience will be more enjoyable. As for Chem Engineering I have no idea being an Economics student.
My answers here are limited since I am an undergrad student, but I love your enthusiasm and eagerness, and wish you the best of luck! Please go easy be nice to your undergrads, I probably know some of them ;)</commentText><authorName>Nois88</authorName><authorID>o6jb3</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487899108.0</commentCreated><commentID>de497iq</commentID><commentText>There are plenty of places to live within walking distance that are suitable for grad students, whether in row houses or apartment buildings. How good or nice it is will just depend on the price range you can work with. But if you want to live a bit further, check out the Mt Vernon area too. You can take the JHMI shuttle to Homewood campus throughout the day. The Mt Vernon and Charles Village areas are safer than where the med school is But in Charles Village you'll just have to deal with having lots of undergrads around too. My Vernon is closer to all the attractions at the inner harbor. If you want something quieter, check out Hampden, it's the neighborhood just northwest of Homewood campus. 

I'm not sure what grad student life is like at Hopkins/ChemBE. But as an undergrad, I thought it was pretty easy making friends just by going to events and joining clubs that were in my areas of interest. Baltimore as a city grows on you. Just be careful when you're walking at night, esp if you're walking alone.</commentText><authorName>hungryhungryhippooo</authorName><authorID>86z7y</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487895005.0</commentCreated><commentID>de45d8g</commentID><commentText>I was at the medical center for most of my time at Hopkins (Health Economics). I felt unsafe in the area, which really made me regret living so close by. Got mugged, my car was broken into twice, teenagers were hiding on my porch to do drugs, it was a bloody nightmare.

If your program is based in Homewood, I'd suggest living in that area, paying slightly more in rent, and knowing that premium goes a long way in paying for peace of mind.

You'll make friends easily enough. Cohorts for PhDs tend to adopt their incomers fairly quick. If you want a social life outside of chemical engineering, your best bet is Tinder. Second to that, there are several interschool events, like speeddating, sponsored happy hours either on campus or at hosting restaurants, and I got one the other day about ice skating in the park I used to live next to.

I didn't enjoy my time in Baltimore. But, one could argue that grad school's not the place to enjoy yourself. I would choose the program all over again most likely though.</commentText><authorName>BadEThrowaway</authorName><authorID>wbula</authorID></comment></comments></submission><submission>5vjx6w<comments><comment><commentCreated>1487825458.0</commentCreated><commentID>de2y90w</commentID><commentText>Sorry to disappoint, but the pasta they have available to add your own sauces/toppings to is generally fairly bland and overcooked. If they make a dish that contains pasta, it's generally slightly better but not restaurant quality.</commentText><authorName>1stbaser</authorName><authorID>j4ffk</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487829266.0</commentCreated><commentID>de31quu</commentID><commentText>Senior here

FFC is one of the things I miss most about freshman year. </commentText><authorName>slthomp2</authorName><authorID>8jyvf</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487843830.0</commentCreated><commentID>de3d73r</commentID><commentText>Freshman here!
1. It is not that great. You can find things that are good and get by, but you'll definitely get sick of it and nothing I've had is great by any means. Late Night has the best food, but it's still just fine. 
2. The pizza is edible but not very good. Someone said that pizza is pretty hard to mess up -- they're right, but the FFC found a way. I'll still eat it when other stuff isn't looking too good, but it is nothing compared to even like Domino's.
3. Meat is hit and miss, depending on the day and the meat. I think the burgers (there everyday) are just terrible, but any pork/beef/chicken daily options have been fine. I don't eat fish, but I've heard that theirs is not good.
4. Pastas are generally fine but a bit bland. The sauce changes everyday and sometimes is weirdly spicy...other times it's very vegetable-y, which I'm fine with.
Overall I'm really not a fan and can't wait to not need to be so dependent upon it anymore. But the tip about the ice cream is true! It's amazing!</commentText><authorName>strukbylightnin</authorName><authorID>k844d</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487852186.0</commentCreated><commentID>de3jds9</commentID><commentText>Thanks guys for the quick replies. </commentText><authorName>bluejay_98</authorName><authorID>15kywc</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487823800.0</commentCreated><commentID>de2wpsd</commentID><commentText>1. It's pretty good. Ranges in quality quite a bit, but the options in the custom section are usually solid. 2. Pizza is pizza. It's pretty hard to mess it up. Not the best, but always a solid option when you're at the FFC. 3. The meat varies quite a bit. You can always get your overcooked burgers, hot dogs, and chicken breasts, but sometimes they offer better options. 4. Pasta is fine. Usually have a couple options and an array of sauces.</commentText><authorName>my_gamertag_wastaken</authorName><authorID>pb85b</authorID></comment><comment><commentCreated>1487835624.0</commentCreated><commentID>de36y9n</commentID><commentText>1. Food is pretty good. By FAR the best thing there is the ice cream. It's from a local place in Baltimore and it's fantastic. I also like being able to make my own omelette at the omelette station for breakfast 
2. I don't really eat the pizza there so can't say 
3. The meat is usually good. Best thing they make is the chicken wings and rotisserie chicken imo. I'd be wary of the fish because sometimes it's really salty
4. The pasta is alright. Best thing might be to make your own pasta mix at the stir fry station </commentText><authorName>IMPERIALteig</authorName><authorID>ff4et</authorID></comment></comments></submission></subreddit></data>